[{ "question":"Cause to feel embarrassed", "answer" : "Abash → शर्मिंदा करना" },
{ "question":"A Place Where Animals Are Slaughtered For The Market", "answer" : "Abattoir → कसाईखाना" },
{ "question":"Shortening Something By Omitting Parts Of It", "answer" : "Abbreviation → संक्षिप्त" },
{ "question":"To Give Up A Throne Voluntarily", "answer" : "Abdicate → त्यागना" },
{ "question":"Voluntary Giving Up Of Throne In Favour Of Someone", "answer" : "Abdication → त्याग" },
{ "question":"Do Away With", "answer" : "Abolish → समाप्त करना" },
{ "question":"The Original Inhabitants Of A Country", "answer" : "Aborigines → मुलनिवासी" },
{ "question":"An Edition A Book In Which It Has Been Condensed", "answer" : "Abridged → संगृहीत" },
{ "question":"To Do Away With Rules", "answer" : "Abrogate → अभिनिषेध करना" },
{ "question":"Move Faster", "answer" : "Accelerate → में तेजी लाने के" },
{ "question":"Which Can Be Approached", "answer" : "Accessible → सुलभ" },
{ "question":"To Accustom Oneself In New Climate", "answer" : "Acclimatize → जलवायु का अभ्यस्त बनाना" },
{ "question":"A Partner In Crime", "answer" : "Accomplice → साथी" },
{ "question":"Responsible For One's Actions", "answer" : "Accountable → उत्तरदायी" },
{ "question":"Make Oneself Familiar With A Person Or A Thing", "answer" : "Acquaint → परिचित" },
{ "question":"The Act Of Freeing A Person From A Charge By Verdict", "answer" : "Acquittal → दोषमुक्ति" },
{ "question":"Someone Versed In The Interpretation Of Numerical Data", "answer" : "Actuary → मुंशी" },
{ "question":"A Substance That Can Stick Or Cause Sticking", "answer" : "Adhesive → गोंद" },
{ "question":"The Period Between The Beginning Of Puberty And Adulthood", "answer" : "Adolescence → किशोरावस्था" },
{ "question":"To Falsify A Thing By Admixture Or Baser Ingredients", "answer" : "Adulteration → मिलावट" },
{ "question":"Person Who Pilots Or Travels In A Balloon Airship Or Other Aircraft", "answer" : "Aeronaut → वायु-यान चलानेवाला" },
{ "question":"Science Of Flight Of Aeroplanes", "answer" : "Aeronautics → एयरोनॉटिक्स" },
{ "question":"Fear Of Height", "answer" : "Aerophobia → ऊंचाई का डर" },
{ "question":"Person Who Claims To Have Great Love For Understanding Of What Is Beautiful In Nature , Art Etc", "answer" : "Aesthete → " },
{ "question":"A List Of Headings Of The Business To Be Transacted At A Meeting", "answer" : "Agenda → कार्यसूची" },
{ "question":"To Increase The Gravity Of An Offence Or The Intensity Of A Disease", "answer" : "Aggravate → छेड़ना" },
{ "question":"Someone Who Attacks", "answer" : "Aggressor → आक्रामक" },
{ "question":"Fear Of Pain", "answer" : "Agliophobia → दर्द से डर" },
{ "question":"A Person Who Claims The Existence Of God Is Unknowable", "answer" : "Agnostic → अज्ञेयवाद का" },
{ "question":"Fear Of Open Spaces Or Crowd", "answer" : "Agoraphobia → भीड़ से डर लगना" },
{ "question":"Belonging To A Foreign Country", "answer" : "Alien → विदेशी" },
{ "question":"Arouse Hostility Or Indifference In", "answer" : "Alienate → हटाना" },
{ "question":"Allowance Paid To Wife On Legal Separation", "answer" : "Alimony → गुजारा भत्ता" },
{ "question":"A Story In Which Ideas Are Symbolised As People", "answer" : "Allegory → रूपक" },
{ "question":"Commencement Of Words With The Same Letter", "answer" : "Alliteration → अनुप्रास" },
{ "question":"An Annual Calender With Positions Of Stars", "answer" : "Almanac → पंचांग" },
{ "question":"A Raised Place On Which Offering To A God Are Made", "answer" : "Altar → वेदी" },
{ "question":"A Person Who Loves Every Body", "answer" : "Altruist → परोपकार के सिद्धन्त का" },
{ "question":"A Lover Of Mankind", "answer" : "Altruist/Philanthropist → एल्ट्रूइस्ट / परोपकारी" },
{ "question":"A Man Who Does A Thing For Pleasure And Not As A Profession", "answer" : "Amateur → शौकिया" },
{ "question":"Fear Of Riding A Car", "answer" : "Amaxophobia → कार चलने का दर" },
{ "question":"One Who Represents A State In A Foreign Country", "answer" : "Ambassador → दूत" },
{ "question":"One, Who Can Use Either Hand With Ease", "answer" : "Ambidexter → " },
{ "question":"Of A Person Who Can Use Both Hands Equally Well", "answer" : "Ambidextrous → कपटी" },
{ "question":"An Expression Or Statement That Has More Than One Meaning", "answer" : "Ambiguity → अस्पष्टता" },
{ "question":"Uncertain Or Unable To Decide About What Course To Follow", "answer" : "Ambivalent → " },
{ "question":"A Van Which Is Used In Transporting Wounded Or Serious Patients", "answer" : "Ambulance → एम्बुलेंस" },
{ "question":"One Who Is Likeable", "answer" : "Amiable → सौम्य" },
{ "question":"Partial Or Total Loss Of Memory", "answer" : "Amnesia → भूलने की बीमारी" },
{ "question":"A Warrant Granting Release From Punishment For An Offense", "answer" : "Amnesty → आम माफ़ी" },

{ "question":"Animals Which Live Both On Land And Sea", "answer" : "Amphibian → उभयचर" },
{ "question":"To Cut Off A Part Of A Person's Body Which Is Infected", "answer" : "Amputate → अंग-विच्छेद करना" },
{ "question":"A Person Or Thing Out Of Time And Out Of Date; Belonging To A Different Era Either Earlier Or Later", "answer" : "Anachronism → कालभ्रम" },
{ "question":"One, Who Is Out To Destroy All Governance, Law And Order", "answer" : "Anarchist → अराजकतावादी" },
{ "question":"A State Of Lawlessness And Disorder", "answer" : "Anarchy → अराजकता" },
{ "question":"Physical Structure", "answer" : "Anatomy → एनाटॉमी" },
{ "question":"Fear Of Males", "answer" : "Androphobia → पुरषों से दर" },
{ "question":"One Who Is Fond Of English People And Their Customs", "answer" : "Anglophile → " },
{ "question":"The Yearly Return Of A Date", "answer" : "Anniversary → सालगिरह" },
{ "question":"Which Happens Once A Year", "answer" : "Annual → वार्षिक" },
{ "question":"Medicine Which Lessens Pain", "answer" : "Anodyne → पीड़ा-नाशक" },
{ "question":"Deviation Or Departure From Common Rule Of Standard", "answer" : "Anomaly → विसंगति" },
{ "question":"Having No Known Name Or Identity Or Known Source", "answer" : "Anonymous → गुमनाम" },
{ "question":"Fear Of Getting Fat Makes Young Girl Stop Eating Resulting Inharmful Effect", "answer" : "Anorexia → आहार" },
{ "question":"Capable Of Being Answered", "answer" : "Answerable → जवाबदेह" },
{ "question":"A Person Who Opposes Another", "answer" : "Antagonist → प्रतिपक्षी" },
{ "question":"Be Earlier In Time; Go Back Further", "answer" : "Antedate → समय से पूर्व घटित होना" },
{ "question":"Room Leading Into A Large Room", "answer" : "Anteroom → गलियारा" },
{ "question":"A Collection Of Poems", "answer" : "Anthology → संकलन" },
{ "question":"Student Of The Development Of The Mankind", "answer" : "Anthropologist → मानवविज्ञानी" },
{ "question":"Science Of The Origins And Social Relationships Of Humans", "answer" : "Anthropology → नृविज्ञान" },
{ "question":"A Remedy That Stops Or Controls The Effects Of A Poison", "answer" : "Antidote → मारक" },
{ "question":"Strong Dislike Or Hostility", "answer" : "Antipathy → घृणा" },
{ "question":"Thoroughly Clean And Free Of Disease-Causing Organisms", "answer" : "Antiseptic → सड़न रोकनेवाली दबा" },
{ "question":"A Word That Expresses An Opposite Meaning", "answer" : "Antonym → विलोम" },
{ "question":"Lack Of Feeling", "answer" : "Apathy → उदासीनता" },
{ "question":"Loss Of Speech", "answer" : "Aphasia → बोली बंद होना" },
{ "question":"That Which Causes Sexual Arousal", "answer" : "Aphrodisiac → कामोद्दीपक" },
{ "question":"One Who Deserts His Religion", "answer" : "Apostate → स्वधर्मत्यागी" },
{ "question":"A Pioneer Of A Reform Movement", "answer" : "Apostle → प्रेरित" },
{ "question":"Be Fully Aware Of", "answer" : "Appreciate → सराहना" },
{ "question":"A Person Who Has Just Started Learning", "answer" : "Apprentice → अपरेंटिस" },
{ "question":"A Place Where Fishes Are Kept", "answer" : "Aquarium → मछलीघर" },
{ "question":"Animals/Plants Ere Which Live In Water", "answer" : "Aquatic → जलीय" },
{ "question":"Fear of spiders", "answer" : "Arachnophobia → मकड़ियों का भय" },
{ "question":"A Person, Appointed By Two Parties To Solve A Dispute", "answer" : "Arbitrator → पंच" },
{ "question":"The Branch Of Anthropology That Studies Prehistoric People", "answer" : "Archaeology → पुरातत्व" },
{ "question":"Words Used In Ancient Time But No Longer In General Use Now", "answer" : "Archaic → प्राचीन" },
{ "question":"One Who Prepares Plans For Buildings", "answer" : "Architect → वास्तुकार" },
{ "question":"A Place Where Government Or Public Records Are Kept", "answer" : "Archives → अभिलेखागार" },
{ "question":"Government By The Nobles", "answer" : "Aristocracy → शिष्टजन" },
{ "question":"The Cessation Of Warfare Before A Treaty Is Signed", "answer" : "Armistice → युद्धविराम" },
{ "question":"A Place For Ammunition And Weapons", "answer" : "Arsenal → आर्सेनल" },
{ "question":"One Who Is Guilty Of Firing Property", "answer" : "Arsonist → " },
{ "question":"One Who Is Not Interested In The Pleasures Of The World", "answer" : "Ascetic → तपस्वी" },
{ "question":"An Assembly Of Hearers", "answer" : "Assemblage → जमावड़ा" },
{ "question":"Star-Shaped Flower", "answer" : "Aster → एस्टर" },
{ "question":"Fear Of Thunder And Lightening", "answer" : "Astraphobia → " },
{ "question":"A Person Who Studies The Influence Of Heavenly Bodies On Human Beings", "answer" : "Astrologer → ज्योतिषी" },
{ "question":"One Who Is Skilled In The Study Of Celestial Bodies", "answer" : "Astronomer → खगोलविद" },

{ "question":"An institution for the maintenance and care of the mentally ill, orphans, or other persons requiring specialized assistance.", "answer" : "Asylum → शरण स्थल" },
{ "question":"A Person Who Does Not Believe In God", "answer" : "Atheist → नास्तिक" },
{ "question":"Fear Of Failure", "answer" : "Atychiphobia → असफ़लता का दर" },
{ "question":"Sound Which Can Be Heard", "answer" : "Audible → सुनाई देने योग्य" },
{ "question":"A Number Of People Listening To A Lecture", "answer" : "Audience → दर्शक" },
{ "question":"The Study Of Hearing, Especially Hearing Defects And Their Treatment", "answer" : "Audiology → ऑडियोलॉजी" },
{ "question":"A Qualified Accountant Who Inspects Accounting Records", "answer" : "Auditor → आडिटर" },
{ "question":"A Specialist With Regard To Ear", "answer" : "Aurist → कान की बीमारियो का जानकार" },
{ "question":"A Life History Written By Oneself", "answer" : "Autobiography → आत्मकथा" },
{ "question":"Government By One Person", "answer" : "Autocracy → एकतंत्र" },
{ "question":"Person Who Rules Without Consulting The Opinion Of Others", "answer" : "Autocrat → अनियन्त्रित शासक" },
{ "question":"Getting Signature Of Some Important Person In His Handwriting", "answer" : "Autograph → हस्ताक्षर" },
{ "question":"Self-Rule", "answer" : "Autonomy → स्वायत्तता" },
{ "question":"Fear Of Being Alone", "answer" : "Autophobia → अकेला होने का दर" },
{ "question":"Reprehensible Acquisitiveness; Insatiable Desire For Wealth", "answer" : "Avarice → लोभ" },
{ "question":"Immoderately Desirous Of Acquiring Something", "answer" : "Avaricious → लालची" },
{ "question":"A Place Where Birds Are Kept", "answer" : "Aviary → पक्षीशाल" },
{ "question":"A Statement Which Is Accepted As True Without Proof", "answer" : "Axiom → स्वयंसिद्ध" },
{ "question":"State Of Being Unmarried", "answer" : "Bachelorhood → अविवाहित्ता" },
{ "question":"A Story In Verse", "answer" : "Ballad → गाथा" },
{ "question":"Science Dealing With The Motion Of Projectile Like Rockets Bombs & Shells", "answer" : "Ballistics → " },
{ "question":"One Who Can’t Pay The Debts", "answer" : "Bankrupt → दिवालिया" },
{ "question":"Fear Of Depths", "answer" : "Bathophobia → गहराई से दर" },
{ "question":"Cut The Head Of", "answer" : "Behead → सिर काट लेना" },
{ "question":"A Person Who Is Fond Of Fighting", "answer" : "Bellicose → लड़ाकू" },
{ "question":"A Person, Nation That Is Involved In War", "answer" : "Belligerent → युद्धरत" },
{ "question":"Nations Engaged In War", "answer" : "Belligerents → " },
{ "question":"Wishing Good Things For Another", "answer" : "Benevolent → उदार" },
{ "question":"To Surround With Armed Forces", "answer" : "Besiege → मुहासिरा करना" },
{ "question":"Engaged To Be Married", "answer" : "Betrothed → मंगेतर" },
{ "question":"A Great Lover Of Books", "answer" : "Bibliophile → पुस्तकों का प्यार करनेवाला" },
{ "question":"An Event Which Happens Once In Two Years", "answer" : "Biennial → द्विवाषिक" },
{ "question":"The Practice Of Having Two Wives Or Husbands At A Time", "answer" : "Bigamy → द्विविवाह का प्रथा" },
{ "question":"One Who Intolerantly Devoted To A Particular Creed", "answer" : "Bigot → कट्टर व्यक्रित" },
{ "question":"Using Or Knowing Two Languages", "answer" : "Bilingual → द्विभाषिक" },
{ "question":"Life Of Person Written By Someone Else", "answer" : "Biography → जीवनी" },
{ "question":"One Who Studies The Science Of Animals And Plants", "answer" : "Biologist → जीवविज्ञानी" },
{ "question":"The Science That Studies Living Organisms", "answer" : "Biology → जीवविज्ञान" },
{ "question":"Examination Of Living Tissue", "answer" : "Biopsy → बायोप्सी" },
{ "question":"Animal Having Two Feet", "answer" : "Biped → दो पैरों का" },
{ "question":"The Act Of Speaking Disrespectfully About Sacred Things", "answer" : "Blasphemy → ईश-निंदा" },
{ "question":"An Unconventional Style Of Living", "answer" : "Bohemian → बोहेनिया का" },
{ "question":"In Good Faith", "answer" : "Bona Fide → प्रामाणिक" },
{ "question":"One Who Devotes Full Time In Studying Course Books", "answer" : "Bookworm → किताबी कीड़ा" },
{ "question":"Clumsy Or Ill‐Bred Fellow", "answer" : "Boor → गंवार" },
{ "question":"One Who Studies The Science Of Plants", "answer" : "Botanist → वनस्पति-विज्ञानिक" },
{ "question":"The Branch Of Biology That Studies Plants", "answer" : "Botany → बॉटनी" },
{ "question":"A Collection Of Flowers", "answer" : "Bouquet → गुलदस्ता" },
{ "question":"Being Of The Property-Owning Class", "answer" : "Bourgeois → पूंजीपति" },
{ "question":"A Small Shop That Sells Fashionable Clothes, Cosmetics Etc", "answer" : "Boutique → बूटिक" },

{ "question":"A Factory For Manufacturing Of Beers", "answer" : "Brewery → शराब की भठ्ठी" },
{ "question":"A Bandit Or Robber, [Esp", "answer" : "Brigand → बटमार" },
{ "question":"Gold Or Silver Before Using For Manufacturing Ornaments", "answer" : "Bullion → बुलियन" },
{ "question":"One Who Comes From A Village And Considered Stupid", "answer" : "Bumpkin → बेढंग आदमी" },
{ "question":"A Small House With All Rooms On One Floor", "answer" : "Bungalow → बंगला" },
{ "question":"A Collection Of Flags", "answer" : "Bunting → गौरेया" },
{ "question":"Government By The Officials", "answer" : "Bureaucracy → नौकरशाही" },
{ "question":"One Who Breaks Into A House To Commit Theft", "answer" : "Burglar → सेंधमार" },
{ "question":"The Dwelling Place If An Animal Underground", "answer" : "Burrow → बिल" },
{ "question":"Person Who Holds Scholarship At A University", "answer" : "Bursar → " },
{ "question":"One Who Kills Animals And Sells Their Flesh", "answer" : "Butcher → कसाई" },
{ "question":"Place Where Cows Are Sheltered", "answer" : "Byre → गोशाला" },
{ "question":"A Place Where Treasurers ,Stores ,Ammunition Are Hidden", "answer" : "Cache → कैश" },
{ "question":"A Person, Who Is Bad In Spellings", "answer" : "Cacographist → " },
{ "question":"Ugly, Illegible Handwriting", "answer" : "Cacography → " },
{ "question":"Fear Of Ugliness", "answer" : "Cacophobia → कुरूपता से दर" },
{ "question":"The Infirmity Of Old Age", "answer" : "Caducity → जरा जीर्णता" },
{ "question":"A Person, Who Writes Beautiful Handwriting", "answer" : "Calligraphist → सुलेखककों" },
{ "question":"Beautiful Handwriting", "answer" : "Calligraphy → सुलेख" },
{ "question":"Having Calluses", "answer" : "Callous → कठोर" },
{ "question":"One, Who Feeds On Human Flesh", "answer" : "Cannibal → नरभक्षक" },
{ "question":"A Lover Of Dogs", "answer" : "Canophilist → कुत्तो से प्यार करनेवाला" },
{ "question":"The Dead Body Of A Animal", "answer" : "Caracas → कराकस" },
{ "question":"A Person, Who Is Specialist In Heart Diseases", "answer" : "Cardiologist → हृदय रोग विशेषज्ञ" },
{ "question":"A Picture Drawn To Make People Laugh", "answer" : "Caricature → कारटूनवाला" },
{ "question":"One, Who Lives On Flesh", "answer" : "Carnivorous → मांसभक्षी" },
{ "question":"One, Who Draws Maps", "answer" : "Cartographer → काटोग्रफ़र" },
{ "question":"A Person Who Os Bad In Spelling", "answer" : "Cartographist → " },
{ "question":"The Art Of Making Maps And Charts", "answer" : "Cartography → नक्शानवीसी" },
{ "question":"A Complete List Of Things, Usually Arranged Systematically", "answer" : "Catalogue → सूची" },
{ "question":"Soldiers, Who Fight On Horse Back", "answer" : "Cavalry → घुड़सवार सेना" },
{ "question":"Abstaining From Sexual Relations", "answer" : "Celibacy → क्वांरापन" },
{ "question":"Abstaining From Sexual Intercourse", "answer" : "Celibate → अविवाहित" },
{ "question":"Extreme Fear Of Beauty", "answer" : "Cellophobia → " },
{ "question":"A Place For Burial Of Dead Bodies", "answer" : "Cemetery → कब्रिस्तान" },
{ "question":"One Who Is More Than A Hundred Years Old", "answer" : "Centenarian → सौ वर्ष का" },
{ "question":"The 100th Anniversary (Or The Celebration Of It)", "answer" : "Centenary → शताब्दी" },
{ "question":"Anything Tending To Move Away From Centre", "answer" : "Centripetal → केंद्राभिगामी" },
{ "question":"One Hundred Years", "answer" : "Century → सदी" },
{ "question":"Elderly Women In Charge Of A Girl On Social Occasions", "answer" : "Chaperon → संरक्षिका" },
{ "question":"Be The Emodment Or Perfect Example Of", "answer" : "Characterise → " },
{ "question":"Person Who Pretends To Have More Knowledge", "answer" : "Charlatan → मायावी" },
{ "question":"An Extremly Deep Crack Or Opening In The Ground", "answer" : "Chasm → खाई" },
{ "question":"One, Who Is Employed To Drive A Motor Car", "answer" : "Chauffeur → ड्राइवर" },
{ "question":"A Person Who Is Blindly Devoted To An Idea", "answer" : "Chauvinist → अंधराष्ट्रीवादी" },
{ "question":"An Unreal And Visionary Ideal", "answer" : "Chimerical → असाध्य" },
{ "question":"A Small Piece Of Wood", "answer" : "Chip → टुकड़ा" },
{ "question":"A Person Who Is An Expert At Penmanship", "answer" : "Chirographer → " },
{ "question":"A Person Who Reads Palms", "answer" : "Chiromancer → " },
{ "question":"Palm-Reading", "answer" : "Chiromancy → कैरोमंसी" },

{ "question":"Specialist Who Takes Care Of The Ailments Of The Feet", "answer" : "Chiropodist → किरोपडिस्ट" },
{ "question":"One, Who Teaches Dancing", "answer" : "Choreographer → कोरियोग्राफर" },
{ "question":"The Science Of Colours", "answer" : "Chromatics → " },
{ "question":"Calendar Of Events In Order Of Occurrence", "answer" : "Chronology → कालक्रम" },
{ "question":"Method Of Talking In A Roundabout Way", "answer" : "Circumlocution → कपटपूर्ण बातें" },
{ "question":"Fear Of Doctors", "answer" : "Claustrophobia → क्लौस्ट्रफ़ोबिया" },
{ "question":"Fear Of Going To Bed", "answer" : "Clinophobia → " },
{ "question":"A Place For Luggage At Railway Station", "answer" : "Cloak Room → लबादा कक्ष" },
{ "question":"An Associate That One Works With", "answer" : "Colleague → सहयोगी" },
{ "question":"People Who Work Together", "answer" : "Colleagues → सहयोगियों" },
{ "question":"Informal Expression Used In Everyday Conversation", "answer" : "Colloquialism → " },
{ "question":"Belong To Same Country", "answer" : "Compatriot → स्वदेशवासी" },
{ "question":"One Who Introduces Performing Artists On The Stage Program", "answer" : "Compere → कमपेरे" },
{ "question":"A Performance Given By A Number Of Musicians", "answer" : "Concert → कॉन्सर्ट" },
{ "question":"Live In Relationship A Man And A Woman Living Without Being Married", "answer" : "Concubinage → बेविवाति साथ रहना" },
{ "question":"A Country Ruled By Two Country", "answer" : "Condominium → सम्मिलित" },
{ "question":"One Who Sells Sweets And Pastries", "answer" : "Confectioner → हलवाई" },
{ "question":"Present At Birth But Not Necessarily Hereditary", "answer" : "Congenital → जन्मजात" },
{ "question":"An Assembly Of Worshippers", "answer" : "Congregation → मण्डली" },
{ "question":"A Critical Judge Of Any Art And Craft", "answer" : "Connoisseur → विशेषज्ञ" },
{ "question":"Relationship By Blood Or Birth", "answer" : "Consanguinity → रक्तसंबंध" },
{ "question":"Compulsory Enlistment For Military Service", "answer" : "Conscription → भरती" },
{ "question":"A Number Of Stars Grounded Together", "answer" : "Constellation → नक्षत्र" },
{ "question":"A Disease Which Spreads By Contact", "answer" : "Contagious → संक्रामक" },
{ "question":"Belonging To Or Living At The Same Time", "answer" : "Contemporaries → समकालीन" },
{ "question":"Belonging to the same period of time", "answer" : "Contemporary → समकालीन" },
{ "question":"Gradual Recovery From Illness", "answer" : "Convalescence → आरोग्यलाभ" },
{ "question":"One, Who Is Recovering Health", "answer" : "Convalescent → अच्छा हो जानेवाला" },
{ "question":"A Funeral Procession Comprising A Number Of Mourners", "answer" : "Cortege → जूलुस" },
{ "question":"Metaphysical Study Of The Origin And Nature Of The Universe", "answer" : "Cosmology → ब्रह्मांड विज्ञान" },
{ "question":"A Person Who Regards Whole World As His Country", "answer" : "Cosmopolitan → कॉस्मोपॉलिटन" },
{ "question":"A Citizen Of The World", "answer" : "Cosmopolite → " },
{ "question":"A Stanza Having Two Lines In Verse", "answer" : "Couplet → दोहा" },
{ "question":"A Nursery Where Children Are Cared For While Their Parents Are At Work", "answer" : "Creche → क्रेच" },
{ "question":"Showing A Lack Of Judgment Or Experience", "answer" : "Credulous → विश्रंभी" },
{ "question":"A Religious War", "answer" : "Crusade → धर्मयुद्ध" },
{ "question":"Study Of Secret Writing And Coded Words", "answer" : "Cryptography → क्रिप्टोग्राफी" },
{ "question":"Science Of Crystallization", "answer" : "Crystallography → क्रि" },
{ "question":"Man Whose Wife Is Unfaithful To Him", "answer" : "Cuckold → व्यभिचारी" },
{ "question":"Which Can Be Cured", "answer" : "Curable → इलाज" },
{ "question":"A Person Incharge Of A Museum", "answer" : "Curator → क्यूरेटर" },
{ "question":"A Low Area Storm With High Winds Rotating About A Centre Of Low Atmospheric Pressure", "answer" : "Cyclone → चक्रवात" },
{ "question":"One, Who Sneers At The Aims And Beliefs Of His Fellow Men", "answer" : "Cynic → निंदक" },
{ "question":"Fear Of Dogs", "answer" : "Cynophobia → " },
{ "question":"Centre Of Attraction", "answer" : "Cynosure → ऋक्ष" },
{ "question":"Study Of Cell", "answer" : "Cytology → कोशिका विज्ञान" },
{ "question":"One Who Pays Too Much Attention To His Cloths And Appearance", "answer" : "Dandy → बांका" },
{ "question":"An Unclaimed Letter", "answer" : "Dead Letter → मृत पत्र" },
{ "question":"One Who Cannot Hear", "answer" : "Deaf → बहरा" },
{ "question":"Prevent A Person From Admission Or A Right", "answer" : "Debar → प्रवेश न होने देना" },

{ "question":"Suave (Polished And Light Heart Person)", "answer" : "Debonair → ख़ुशमिज़ाज" },
{ "question":"A Period Of Ten Years", "answer" : "Decade → दशक" },
{ "question":"An Original Glass Bottle For Holding Wine Or Other Alcoholic Drinks", "answer" : "Decanter → कंटर" },
{ "question":"Act Or Art Of Rhetorical Exercise", "answer" : "Declamation → शब्दपांडित्य" },
{ "question":"A Person Appointed Or Elected To Represent Others", "answer" : "Delegate → प्रतिनिधि" },
{ "question":"A Political Leader Who Tries To Stir Up People", "answer" : "Demagogue → दुर्जनों का नेता" },
{ "question":"The Orientation Of Those Who Favor Government By The People", "answer" : "Democracy → जनतंत्र" },
{ "question":"Science Of Vital And Social Statistics", "answer" : "Demography → जनसांख्यिकी" },
{ "question":"Show Of Force To Intimidate", "answer" : "Demonstration → प्रदर्शन" },
{ "question":"The Home Of A Large Fierce Wild Animal", "answer" : "Den → मांद" },
{ "question":"A Person Who Gives Written Testimony For Use In A Court", "answer" : "Deponent → साक्षी" },
{ "question":"Lose In Value", "answer" : "Depreciate → पछताना" },
{ "question":"A Doctor Who Treats Skin Diseases", "answer" : "Dermatologist → त्वचा विशेषज्ञ" },
{ "question":"Study Of Skin", "answer" : "Dermatology → त्वचा विज्ञान" },
{ "question":"To Derive A Thing Of Its Holy Character", "answer" : "Desecrate → अपवित्र करना" },
{ "question":"Where Neither Water Nor Vegetation Is Found", "answer" : "Desert → रेगिस्तान" },
{ "question":"A form of government in which a single entity rules with absolute power.", "answer" : "Despotism → तानाशाही" },
{ "question":"One Whose Business Is To Find Out Criminals", "answer" : "Detective → जासूसी" },
{ "question":"Become Worse Or Disintegrate", "answer" : "Deteriorate → बिगड़ना" },
{ "question":"State Of Being Split Into Two Parts", "answer" : "Dichotomy → विरोधाभास" },
{ "question":"One Who Gives Orders In A Manner That Permits No Refusal", "answer" : "Dictator → तानाशाह" },
{ "question":"Government Carried On By An Absolute Ruler", "answer" : "Dictatorship → अधिनायकत्व" },
{ "question":"A Book Dealing With Words In Alphabetical Order", "answer" : "Dictionary → शब्दकोश" },
{ "question":"A Small Allowance Of Food To Become Slim", "answer" : "Dieting → परहेज़" },
{ "question":"That Which Can Be Digested", "answer" : "Digestible → सुपाच्य" },
{ "question":"A Dabbler In The Arts", "answer" : "Dilettante → अनुरागी" },
{ "question":"Morbid Compulsion Of Drink", "answer" : "Dipsomania → मद्यासक्ति" },
{ "question":"Fear Of Thirst", "answer" : "Dipsophobia → " },
{ "question":"Song Sung At Burial", "answer" : "Dirge → मरसिया" },
{ "question":"One Who Works In Return For Being Taught The Trade", "answer" : "Disciple → शिष्य" },
{ "question":"That Which Can Be Divided", "answer" : "Divisible → भाज्य" },
{ "question":"A Person Living Permanently In A Certain Place", "answer" : "Domicile → अधिवास" },
{ "question":"The Sleeping Rooms With Several Beds Especially In A College Or Institution", "answer" : "Dormitory → छात्रावास" },
{ "question":"Old Age When A Man Behave Like A Fool", "answer" : "Dotage → मतिक्षीणता" },
{ "question":"The House Of An Arab", "answer" : "Dower → दहेज" },
{ "question":"A Game In Which Neither Party Wins", "answer" : "Draw → खींचना" },
{ "question":"A Game That Results Neither In Victory Nor In Defeat", "answer" : "Drawn → नंगी" },
{ "question":"A Game Or Batter In Which Neither Party Wins", "answer" : "Drawn/ Tie → नंगी / टाई" },
{ "question":"A Squirrel’s Home", "answer" : "Dray → छकड़ा" },
{ "question":"Mania For Travel", "answer" : "Dromomania → " },
{ "question":"Continuous Dry Weather And Lack Of Rain And Water", "answer" : "Drought → सूखा" },
{ "question":"One Who Deals In Cattle", "answer" : "Drover → चौपायों को बेचनेवाला" },
{ "question":"One Who Cannot Speak", "answer" : "Dumb → गूंगा" },
{ "question":"A Person Who Is Slow In Learning", "answer" : "Dunce → कुंद" },
{ "question":"Not Conforming To Ordinary Rules Of Behaviour", "answer" : "Eccentric → विलक्षण" },
{ "question":"One Who Studies The Science Relating To The Church", "answer" : "Ecclesiologist → " },
{ "question":"One who studies the science relating to the church.", "answer" : "Ecclesiologist → गिरजा शिल्पविद" },
{ "question":"Persons with unusual or odd personality.", "answer" : "Eclectic → " },
{ "question":"A pastoral poem.", "answer" : "Eclogue → " },
{ "question":"The Environment As It Relates To Living Organisms", "answer" : "Ecology → परिस्थितिकी" },

{ "question":"Fear Of Home Surroundings", "answer" : "Ecophobia → " },
{ "question":"Fit To Be Eaten", "answer" : "Edible → खाद्य" },
{ "question":"A Person Who Is Womanish", "answer" : "Effeminate → स्रैण" },
{ "question":"Sure To Produce Desired Results", "answer" : "Efficacious → प्रभावोत्पादक" },
{ "question":"A Man Who Thinks Only For Himself", "answer" : "Egoist → अहंवादी" },
{ "question":"Practice Of Talking Too Much About Oneself", "answer" : "Egotism → अहंकार" },
{ "question":"Expressing sorrow or lamentation.", "answer" : "Elegiac → शोक" },
{ "question":"A Poem Of Lamentation", "answer" : "Elegy → शोकगीत" },
{ "question":"Qualified For Or Allowed Or Worthy Of Being Chosen", "answer" : "Eligible → योग्य" },
{ "question":"The Art Of Effective Speaking", "answer" : "Elocution → वाग्मिता" },
{ "question":"Make Clear And Comprehensible", "answer" : "Elucidate → स्पष्ट करना" },
{ "question":"The Fraudulent Appropriation Of Funds Or Property", "answer" : "Embezzlement → ग़बन" },
{ "question":"A Person Who Leaves His Own Country And Goes To Live In Another", "answer" : "Emigrant → प्रवासी" },
{ "question":"Identification With Another Person's Feelings", "answer" : "Empathy → सहानुभूति" },
{ "question":"To Stress, Single Out As Important", "answer" : "Emphasize → ज़ोर देना" },
{ "question":"One Who Employs", "answer" : "Employer → नियोक्ता" },
{ "question":"A Book That Contains Information On Various Subjects", "answer" : "Encyclopaedia → मकदूनियाई" },
{ "question":"A Disease Prevailing In A Locality", "answer" : "Endemic → स्थानिक" },
{ "question":"One Who Studies Insects", "answer" : "Entomologist → कीटविज्ञानशास्री" },
{ "question":"The Scientific Study Of Insects", "answer" : "Entomology → कीटविज्ञान" },
{ "question":"Lasting One Day", "answer" : "Ephemeral → अल्पकालिक" },
{ "question":"A Long Narrative Poem", "answer" : "Epic → महाकाव्य" },
{ "question":"One, Who Is Devoted To The Pleasure Of Eating And Drinking", "answer" : "Epicure → रसिया" },
{ "question":"One Whose Attitude Is To Eat, Drink And Merry", "answer" : "Epicurean → एपिकुरे" },
{ "question":"A Widespread Outbreak Of An Infectious Disease", "answer" : "Epidemic → महामारी" },
{ "question":"Outer Layer Of Skin", "answer" : "Epidermis → एपिडर्मिस" },
{ "question":"A Verse Letter", "answer" : "Epistle → पत्र" },
{ "question":"Words Which Are Inscribed On The Grave Or The Tomb In The Memory Of The Buried", "answer" : "Epitaph → समाधि-लेख" },
{ "question":"Calmness Under Trying Circumstances", "answer" : "Equanimity → समभाव" },
{ "question":"A Person Who Rides On Horse-Back", "answer" : "Equestrian → घुड़सवार" },
{ "question":"Having Equal Sides", "answer" : "Equilateral → समभुज" },
{ "question":"Tightrope Walker", "answer" : "Equilibrist → नट" },
{ "question":"A State Of Perfect Balance", "answer" : "Equilibrium → संतुलन" },
{ "question":"Time When Night And Day Are Of Equal Length", "answer" : "Equinox → विषुव" },
{ "question":"Destroy Completely, As If Down To The Roots", "answer" : "Eradicate → उन्मूलन" },
{ "question":"Fear Of Work", "answer" : "Ergophobia → " },
{ "question":"Thing Without Which We Cannot Do", "answer" : "Essential → आवश्यक" },
{ "question":"Having No Beginning Or End To Its Existence", "answer" : "Eternal → सनातन" },
{ "question":"One Who Studies The Science Of The Variatees Of Human Race", "answer" : "Ethnologist → " },
{ "question":"Branch Of Anthropology Dealing With Divisions Of Humankind", "answer" : "Ethnology → मानव जाति विज्ञान" },
{ "question":"One Who Studies The Science Of Character", "answer" : "Ethologist → " },
{ "question":"Rules Governing Socially Acceptable Behavior", "answer" : "Etiquette → शिष्टाचार" },
{ "question":"One Who Studies The Science And Origin Of Words", "answer" : "Etymologist → शब्द-व्युपत्तिशास्री" },
{ "question":"Science Relating To The Formation And Development Of Words", "answer" : "Etymology → शब्द-साधन" },
{ "question":"A Formal Expression Of Praise For Someone Who Has Died", "answer" : "Eulogy → स्तवन" },
{ "question":"Thing That Bring Gentle And Painless Death From Incurable Disease", "answer" : "Euthanasia → इच्छामृत्यु" },
{ "question":"Science Of Improving The Environment", "answer" : "Euthenics → " },
{ "question":"A Gradual Upholding Or Development", "answer" : "Evolution → विकास" },
{ "question":"One Who Is Taking Examination", "answer" : "Examinee → परीक्षार्थी" },
{ "question":"One Who Examine The Copies Of Examinees", "answer" : "Examiner → परीक्षक" },

{ "question":"A word meaning happy and joyful", "answer" : "Exhilarated → ख़ुश" },
{ "question":"Made To Be Absent For A Long Time From One's Own Country", "answer" : "Exile → निर्वासन" },
{ "question":"Science Dealing With Life Or Possibilities Of Life Existing Beyond The Earth", "answer" : "Exobiology → " },
{ "question":"A Specialist Who Extracts Teeth", "answer" : "Exodontist → " },
{ "question":"Pronounce Not Guilty Of Criminal Charges", "answer" : "Exonerate → हक़ बहाल करना" },
{ "question":"To Atone One’s Sins", "answer" : "Expiate → निवृत्त" },
{ "question":"To Remove All Objectionable Matter", "answer" : "Expurgate → " },
{ "question":"With Little Or No Preparation Or Forethought", "answer" : "Extempore → अचिंतित" },
{ "question":"To Send Back The Criminal To The Country", "answer" : "Extradite → अपराधी देना" },
{ "question":"Forcing Out(Blood Etc", "answer" : "Extravasate → " },
{ "question":"free someone or something from a constraint or difficulty.", "answer" : "Extricate → सुलझाना" },
{ "question":"One Who Turns One's Thoughts Outwards", "answer" : "Extrovert → बहिर्मुखी" },
{ "question":"An Animal Story With Moral", "answer" : "Fable → कल्पित कहानी" },
{ "question":"An Exact Copy Of Handwriting, Printing Etc", "answer" : "Facsimile → प्रतिकृति" },
{ "question":"An Exact Copy Of Handwriting ,Printing", "answer" : "Facsimile/Xerox → प्रतिकृति" },
{ "question":"A Person Motivated By Irrational Enthusiasm", "answer" : "Fanatic → हठधर्मी" },
{ "question":"One, Who Is Filled With Excessive And Mistaken Enthusiasm In Religious Matters", "answer" : "Fanatic Or Bigot → कट्टरपंथी या Bigot" },
{ "question":"One Who Shoes Horses", "answer" : "Farrier → नालबन्द" },
{ "question":"One, Who Is Very -Selective In One's Taste", "answer" : "Fastidious → दुराराध्य" },
{ "question":"Causing Death", "answer" : "Fatal → घातक" },
{ "question":"One, Who Believes In Fate", "answer" : "Fatalist → भाग्यवादी" },
{ "question":"The Animals Of A Certain Region", "answer" : "Fauna → पशुवर्ग" },
{ "question":"Congrulations Some One In Formal Manner", "answer" : "Felicitated → को सम्मानित किया" },
{ "question":"One, Who Works For The Welfare Of The Women", "answer" : "Feminist → नारीवादी" },
{ "question":"Faithfulness", "answer" : "Fidelity → सत्य के प्रति निष्ठा" },
{ "question":"Murder Of One’s Children", "answer" : "Filicide → " },
{ "question":"A Number Of Sheeps", "answer" : "Flock → झुण्ड" },
{ "question":"The Plants Of A Particular Region", "answer" : "Flora → फ्लोरा" },
{ "question":"One, Who Deals-In Flowers", "answer" : "Florist → फूलवाला" },
{ "question":"A person who support or believe someone.", "answer" : "Follower → अनुयायी" },
{ "question":"Well In The Past; Former", "answer" : "Foregone → पहले से" },
{ "question":"Falsification Of Documents Etc", "answer" : "Forgery → जालसाजी" },
{ "question":"Remains Of Prehistoric Animal Or Plant Preserved By Being Buried In Earth", "answer" : "Fossils → जीवाश्म" },
{ "question":"Child Brought By Persons, Who Are Not His Parents", "answer" : "Foster Child → धाय पालित संतान" },
{ "question":"Easily Broken", "answer" : "Fragile → नाज़ुक" },
{ "question":"Constitutional Right To Cast Vote", "answer" : "Franchise → मताधिकार" },
{ "question":"Murder Of Brother", "answer" : "Fratricide → भ्रातृघातक" },
{ "question":"One, Who Runs Away From Justice Or The Law", "answer" : "Fugitive → भगोड़ा" },
{ "question":"The Line Which A Plough Cuts In The Ground", "answer" : "Furrow → कुंड" },
{ "question":"Irregular Luminous Band Of Stars", "answer" : "Galaxy → आकाशगंगा" },
{ "question":"Fear Of Marriage", "answer" : "Gamophobia → " },
{ "question":"A Shed For Motor Car", "answer" : "Garage → गेराज" },
{ "question":"A Government Publication Relating To Order, Notification Etc", "answer" : "Gazette → राज-पत्र" },
{ "question":"Study Of Ancestry", "answer" : "Genealogy → वंशावली" },
{ "question":"Science Of Heredity", "answer" : "Genetics → जेनेटिक्स" },
{ "question":"Murder Of Race", "answer" : "Genocide → नरसंहार" },
{ "question":"Fear Of Birth", "answer" : "Genophobia → " },
{ "question":"Fear Of Sex", "answer" : "Genophobia → विदेशी लोगों को न पसन्द करना" },
{ "question":"One Who Studies The Earth", "answer" : "Geologist → भूविज्ञानी" },
{ "question":"The Study Of Rocks And Soils", "answer" : "Geology → भूविज्ञान" },

{ "question":"Fear Of Old Age", "answer" : "Geraphobia → " },
{ "question":"Specialty Dealing With The Medical Problems Of The Elderly", "answer" : "Geriatrics → जराचिकित्सा" },
{ "question":"An Agent (As Heat Or Radiation Or A Chemical) That Destroys Microorganisms That Might Carry Disease", "answer" : "Germicide → अंकुर-नाशक दवा" },
{ "question":"Government By Old Man", "answer" : "Gerontocracy → " },
{ "question":"Science Of The Social And Economic Problems Of The Aged", "answer" : "Gerontology → जरा विज्ञान" },
{ "question":"A Mass Of Ice Moving Very Slowly Down A Mountain Valley", "answer" : "Glacier → हिमनद" },
{ "question":"White Liquid Material In An Egg", "answer" : "Glair → कीचड़" },
{ "question":"List Of Explantation", "answer" : "Glossary → शब्दकोष" },
{ "question":"A Person Who Is Devoted To Eating And Drinking To Excess", "answer" : "Glutton → खाऊ" },
{ "question":"Art And Science Dealing With A Language", "answer" : "Grammar → व्याकरण" },
{ "question":"A Place For Grains", "answer" : "Granary → धान्यागार" },
{ "question":"One Who Analyzes Hand-Writing", "answer" : "Graphologist → " },
{ "question":"Analysis Of Handwriting", "answer" : "Graphology → हस्तलेख का अध्ययन" },
{ "question":"Costing Nothing", "answer" : "Gratis → नि: शुल्क" },
{ "question":"The Place In The Ground Where A Dead Person Is Buried", "answer" : "Grave → गंभीर" },
{ "question":"Make-Up Room Behind Stage", "answer" : "Greenroom → हरा कक्ष" },
{ "question":"Animals Which Live In Flocks", "answer" : "Gregarious → झुण्ड में रहनेवाला" },
{ "question":"Animals Which Live In A Flock , Used For Human Beings Also", "answer" : "Gregarious/Sociable → यूथचारी / मिलनसार" },
{ "question":"Naive And Easily Deceived Or Tricked", "answer" : "Gullible → भोला" },
{ "question":"A Sudden Rush Of Wind", "answer" : "Gust → झोंका" },
{ "question":"The Specialist Who Treats The Female Reproductive And Sexual Organs", "answer" : "Gynaecologist → स्त्री रोग विशेषज्ञ" },
{ "question":"Fear Of Women", "answer" : "Gynophobia → " },
{ "question":"An Instrument For Recodings The Revolutions Of The Earth", "answer" : "Gyroscope → जाइरोस्कोप" },
{ "question":"The Normal Abode Of Any Animal Or Plant", "answer" : "Habitat → वास" },
{ "question":"Calm And Peaceful", "answer" : "Halcyon → धीर" },
{ "question":"A Person Without Objective Reality", "answer" : "Hallucination → माया" },
{ "question":"A Place For Housing Aeroplanes", "answer" : "Hangar → हैंगर" },
{ "question":"Two Wheeled Cab For Two To Ride Indie With Driver Mounted Up Behind", "answer" : "Hansom → इक्का" },
{ "question":"Loud Talk Or Speech", "answer" : "Harangue → भाषण" },
{ "question":"A Women Of Lax Moral", "answer" : "Harlot → रंडी" },
{ "question":"Fear Of Being Robbed", "answer" : "Harpaxophobia → " },
{ "question":"A Vehicle Which Is Used To Carry A Dead Body", "answer" : "Hearse → रथी" },
{ "question":"One, Who Believes That Pleasure Is The Chief Good (Sensual)", "answer" : "Hedonist → सुखवादी" },
{ "question":"Fear Of Pleasure", "answer" : "Hedonophobia → " },
{ "question":"Wicked To A High Degree", "answer" : "Heinous → जघन्य" },
{ "question":"A Place For The Collection Of Dried Plants", "answer" : "Herbarium → सूखी वनस्पतियों का संग्राह" },
{ "question":"One, Who Lives On Herbs", "answer" : "Herbivorous → तृणभक्षी" },
{ "question":"Belief Or Opinion Contrary To What Is Generally Accepted", "answer" : "Heresy → विधर्म" },
{ "question":"One, Who Acts Against Religion", "answer" : "Heretic → विधर्मी" },
{ "question":"Creature Havingh Both Male And Female Organs", "answer" : "Hermaphrodite → द्विलिंग" },
{ "question":"Things Of Different Nature", "answer" : "Heterogeneous → विजातीय" },
{ "question":"A Person Claiming To Be Superior In Culture And Intellect To Others", "answer" : "Highbrow → घमंडी" },
{ "question":"One Who Robs Smuggler Of His Smuggled Goods After The Border Has Been Crossed", "answer" : "Hijacker → लुटेरा" },
{ "question":"Person Who Is Against The Ordinary Society Esp", "answer" : "Hippy → हिप्पी" },
{ "question":"Study Of Tissue", "answer" : "Histology → प्रोटोकॉल" },
{ "question":"A Place For Bees", "answer" : "Hive → मधुमुखी का छत्ता" },
{ "question":"Murder Of Man", "answer" : "Homicide → मानव हत्या" },
{ "question":"Thing Of Same Nature", "answer" : "Homogeneous → सजातीय" },
{ "question":"The First Night Of Newly Married Couple", "answer" : "Honeymoon → सुहाग रात" },
{ "question":"Holding Office Without Any Remuneration", "answer" : "Honorary → माननीय" },

{ "question":"A Line At Which The Earth And The Sky Seem To Meet", "answer" : "Horizon → क्षितिज" },
{ "question":"The Art Of Cultivating And Managing Gardens", "answer" : "Horticulture → बागवानी" },
{ "question":"Fond Of Entertaining Guests", "answer" : "Hospitable → मेहमाननवाज़" },
{ "question":"A State Of Deep-Seated Ill-Will", "answer" : "Hostility → शत्रुता" },
{ "question":"Seat On Elephant’s Back", "answer" : "Howdah → " },
{ "question":"Marked By Devotion To Popular Welfare", "answer" : "Humanitarian → मानवीय" },
{ "question":"Assembly Or Parliament In Which No Party Has Got Clear Majority", "answer" : "Hung → त्रिशंकु" },
{ "question":"A Box Or Cage For Keeping Rabbits", "answer" : "Hutch → हच" },
{ "question":"A Serpent With Many Heads", "answer" : "Hydra → हीड्रा" },
{ "question":"Fear Of Travel", "answer" : "Hydrophobia → जलांतक" },
{ "question":"A Specialist In The Promotion Of Clean Conditions For The Preservation Of Health", "answer" : "Hygienist → " },
{ "question":"A Religious Song", "answer" : "Hymn → स्तोत्र" },
{ "question":"A Persistent Anxiety About One’s Health Usually Involving Imagined Symptoms Of Illness", "answer" : "Hypochondria → " },
{ "question":"One Who Is Excessively Worried About One's Health", "answer" : "Hypochondriac → " },
{ "question":"One Who Pretends To Be What He Is Not", "answer" : "Hypocrite → पाखंडी" },
{ "question":"A Tentative Assumption, Made To Drive A Logical Conclusion", "answer" : "Hypothesis → परिकल्पना" },
{ "question":"A Person Who Attacks Popular Belief Or Established Custom", "answer" : "Iconoclast → मूर्तिभंजक" },
{ "question":"An Odd, A Typical Or Eccentric Trait", "answer" : "Idiosyncrasy → लत" },
{ "question":"The Worship Of Idols Or Images That Are Not God", "answer" : "Idolatry → मूर्ति पूजा" },
{ "question":"Short Descriptive Poem Or Picturesque Scene Or Incident", "answer" : "Idyll → सुखद जीवन" },
{ "question":"A house where an Eskimo lives.", "answer" : "Igloo → एस्किमों का घर" },
{ "question":"Person Having No Knowledge Of Any Happening", "answer" : "Ignorant → अनजान" },
{ "question":"Prohibited By Law Or By Official Or Accepted Rules", "answer" : "Illegal → अवैध" },
{ "question":"Incapable Of Being Read", "answer" : "Illegible → अस्पष्ट" },
{ "question":"Which Can Be Imitated", "answer" : "Imitable → अनुगमनीय" },
{ "question":"A Person Who Is Pure And Clean", "answer" : "Immaculate → शुद्ध" },
{ "question":"A Person Who Comes To One Country From Another In Order To Settle There", "answer" : "Immigrant → आप्रवासी" },
{ "question":"Which Cannot Be Moved, Fixed", "answer" : "Immovable → अचल" },
{ "question":"Free From Infection", "answer" : "Immune → इम्यून" },
{ "question":"Incapable Of Being Penetrated", "answer" : "Impenetrable → अभेद्य" },
{ "question":"Impossible Or Difficult To Sense", "answer" : "Imperceptible → अगोचर" },
{ "question":"Not Admitting Of Passage Or Capable Of Being Affected", "answer" : "Impervious → प्रबल" },
{ "question":"A Person Pretending To Be Somebody He Is Not", "answer" : "Imposter → ढोंगी" },
{ "question":"Incapable Of Being Practised", "answer" : "Impracticable → अव्यवहारिक" },
{ "question":"Having A Chance Of Occurring Too Low To Inspire Belief", "answer" : "Improbable → असंभव" },
{ "question":"That Cannot Be Easily Approached", "answer" : "Inaccessible → दुर्गम" },
{ "question":"Incapable Of Being Admitted Or Allowed", "answer" : "Inadmissible → अस्वीकार्य" },
{ "question":"Something That Cannot Be Taken Away", "answer" : "Inalienable → अविच्छेद्य" },
{ "question":"Not Endowed With Life", "answer" : "Inanimate → अचेतन" },
{ "question":"A Sound That Cannot Be Heard", "answer" : "Inaudible → अश्राव्य" },
{ "question":"A Person Who Maliciously Destroys By Fire", "answer" : "Incendiary → आग लगानेवाला" },
{ "question":"Travelling Under Another Name Than One's Own", "answer" : "Incognito → गुप्त" },
{ "question":"Incapable Of Being Burnt", "answer" : "Incombustible → " },
{ "question":"Difficult To Understand", "answer" : "Incomprehensible → समझ से बाहर" },
{ "question":"Out Of Place", "answer" : "Incongruous → बेमेल" },
{ "question":"State Of Being Beyond Reform Or Correction", "answer" : "Incorrigibility → " },
{ "question":"Incapable Of Being Corrected", "answer" : "Incorrigible → असंशोधनीय" },
{ "question":"Beyond Belief Or Understanding", "answer" : "Incredible → अतुल्य" },
{ "question":"Incapable Of Being Remedied", "answer" : "Incurable → लाइलाज" },
{ "question":"One, Who Does Not Tire Easily", "answer" : "Indefatigable → अथक" },

{ "question":"Not Able To Be Protected Against Attack", "answer" : "Indefensible → असमर्थनीय" },
{ "question":"That Cannot Be Erased", "answer" : "Indelible → अमिट" },
{ "question":"Defying Expression", "answer" : "Indescribable → अवर्णनीय" },
{ "question":"Incapable Of Being Destroyed", "answer" : "Indestructible → अक्षय" },
{ "question":"Incapable Of Being Divided", "answer" : "Indivisible → अभाज्यता" },
{ "question":"Something Carried On Within Door Or Under Cover", "answer" : "Indoor → इंडोर" },
{ "question":"Not Suitable To Be Eaten", "answer" : "Inedible → अखाद्य" },
{ "question":"Not Being Able To Be Elected Or Selected Under The Rules", "answer" : "Ineligible → अनुचित" },
{ "question":"Incapable Of Being Avoided", "answer" : "Inevitable → अपरिहार्य" },
{ "question":"Incapable Of Being Justified", "answer" : "Inexcusable → अक्षम्य" },
{ "question":"One Who Is Unrelenting And Cannot Be Moved By Entreaties", "answer" : "Inexorable → निष्ठुर" },
{ "question":"Incapable Of Being Explained Or Accounted For", "answer" : "Inexplicable → अकथनीय" },
{ "question":"One, Who Is Free From All Mistakes And Failures", "answer" : "Infallible → अचूक" },
{ "question":"Murder Of An Infant", "answer" : "Infanticide → भ्रूण हत्या" },
{ "question":"Soldiers, Who Fight On Foot", "answer" : "Infantry → पैदल सेना" },
{ "question":"A Disease Spread By Contact", "answer" : "Infection → संक्रमण" },
{ "question":"Faithlessness", "answer" : "Infidelity → बेवफ़ाई" },
{ "question":"Not Limited By Person Or Number", "answer" : "Infinite → अनंत" },
{ "question":"A Home Or Room Used For Ill Or Injured People", "answer" : "Infirmary → दुर्बलता" },
{ "question":"Liable To Catch Fire Easily", "answer" : "Inflammable → ज्वलनशील" },
{ "question":"Matchless", "answer" : "Inimitable → अनोखी" },
{ "question":"Place Which Provides Both Board And Lodging", "answer" : "Inn → इन" },
{ "question":"That Which Kill Insects", "answer" : "Insecticide → कीटनाशक" },
{ "question":"Incapable Of Being Dissolved", "answer" : "Insoluble → अघुलनशील" },
{ "question":"A Person Who Is Unable To Pay His Debts", "answer" : "Insolvent/Bankrupt → दिवालिया / दिवालिया" },
{ "question":"Inability To Fall Asleep", "answer" : "Insomnia → अनिद्रा" },
{ "question":"One Who Cannot Fall Asleep", "answer" : "Insomniac → इन्सोम्नियाक" },
{ "question":"Interested Mainly In A Small Group Country Etc", "answer" : "Insular → द्वीपीय" },
{ "question":"To Mediate Between Two Parties In A Dispute", "answer" : "Intercede → रक्षा करना" },
{ "question":"Inserting New Matter In A Book", "answer" : "Interpolate → बैठाना" },
{ "question":"A Period Of Interval Between Two Reigns Or Governments", "answer" : "Interregnum → दो राजाए के भीतर समय" },
{ "question":"Anything Pushed Inside Veins", "answer" : "Intervene → हस्तक्षेप करना" },
{ "question":"Having Made No Legally Valid Will Before Death Or Not Disposed Of By A Legal Will", "answer" : "Intestate → बिना वसीयतनामा मारा हुआ" },
{ "question":"Contemplation Of Your Own Thoughts And Desires And Conduct", "answer" : "Introspection → आत्मनिरीक्षण" },
{ "question":"One Who Turns One's Thoughts Inwards", "answer" : "Introvert → अंतर्मुखी" },
{ "question":"One, Who Supervises In The Examination Hall", "answer" : "Invigilator → निरीक्षक" },
{ "question":"One, Too Strong To Be Overcome", "answer" : "Invincible → अजेय" },
{ "question":"Something That Can Not Be Harmed", "answer" : "Inviolate → अक्षत" },
{ "question":"Impossible Or Nearly Impossible To See", "answer" : "Invisible → अदृश्य" },
{ "question":"Incapable Of Being Reconciled", "answer" : "Irreconcilable → कट्टर विरोधी" },
{ "question":"Incapable Of Recovered, Regained", "answer" : "Irrecoverable → अप्रतिलभ्य" },
{ "question":"Having No Bearing On Or Connection With The Subject At Issue", "answer" : "Irrelevant → असंगत" },
{ "question":"Incapable Of Being Repaired", "answer" : "Irreparable → अपूरणीय" },
{ "question":"Easily Annoyed", "answer" : "Irritable → चिड़चिड़ा" },
{ "question":"Government By All", "answer" : "Isocracy → " },
{ "question":"One, Who Journeys From Place To Place", "answer" : "Itinerant → चलनेवाला" },
{ "question":"A Plan For Or Route To Be Followed On A Journy", "answer" : "Itinerary → यात्रा कार्यक्रम" },
{ "question":"A Place Where Prisoners Are Kept", "answer" : "Jail → जेल" },
{ "question":"Language Difficult To Understand", "answer" : "Jargon → शब्दजाल" },
{ "question":"A Short Journy For Pleasure", "answer" : "Jaunt → मनोरंजन की यात्रा" },

{ "question":"A Professional Rider In Horse Races", "answer" : "Jockey → जॉकी" },
{ "question":"A Group Of People Who Band Together For Some Secret Purpose Especially For Political Intrigue", "answer" : "Junta → जून्टा" },
{ "question":"The Territory Within Which Power Can Be Exercised", "answer" : "Jurisdiction → अधिकार क्षेत्र" },
{ "question":"Science Of Law", "answer" : "Jurisprudence → धर्मशास्र" },
{ "question":"Anything Which Relates To Young And Youth", "answer" : "Juvenile → किशोर" },
{ "question":"Government By The Worst Citizen", "answer" : "Kakistocracy → " },
{ "question":"A Swiftly Changing Scene Or Pattern", "answer" : "Kaleidoscope → बहुरूपदर्शक" },
{ "question":"An Animal Of Australia With Great Leaping Power", "answer" : "Kangaroo → कंगेरू" },
{ "question":"Fear Of Cockroaches", "answer" : "Katsaridaphobia → " },
{ "question":"A Place For Dogs", "answer" : "Kennel → कुत्ता-घर" },
{ "question":"Take Away To An Undisclosed Location Against Their Will And Usually In Order To Extract A Ransom", "answer" : "Kidnap → अपहरण करना" },
{ "question":"A School For Small Children", "answer" : "Kindergarten → बाल विहार" },
{ "question":"An Abnormal Desire To Steal", "answer" : "Kleptomania → क्लेपटोमानीया" },
{ "question":"A person who cannot help but steal whatever he can find.", "answer" : "kleptomaniac → " },
{ "question":"A Funeral Bell", "answer" : "Knell → समाधिवाली झंकार" },
{ "question":"Fear Of Speed", "answer" : "Lalophobia → " },
{ "question":"A Written Attack Using Humour To Provoke Contempt", "answer" : "Lampoon → निन्दालेख" },
{ "question":"One, Who Cuts Precious Stones", "answer" : "Lapidist → " },
{ "question":"Established By Or Founded Upon Law Or Official Rules", "answer" : "Legal → कानूनी" },
{ "question":"Responsible According To Law", "answer" : "Legitimate → वैध" },
{ "question":"One, Who Compiles A Dictionary", "answer" : "Lexicographer → कोशकार" },
{ "question":"A False Written Statement To Damage A Person’s Repute", "answer" : "Libel → परिवाद" },
{ "question":"A Person Who Leads An Immoral Life", "answer" : "Libertine/Lecher → अनैतिक / ज़िनाकार" },
{ "question":"Man Of Lax Moral", "answer" : "Licentious → बेलगाम" },
{ "question":"To Comenasate A Person Etc", "answer" : "Lindemnify → " },
{ "question":"One, Who Is Skilled In Foreign Languages", "answer" : "Linguist → भाषाविद" },
{ "question":"Fear Of Getting Fat", "answer" : "Lipophobia → " },
{ "question":"One Who Studies The Science Of Rocks And Minerates", "answer" : "Lithologist → " },
{ "question":"Cutting For Stone In The Bladder", "answer" : "Lithotomy → लिफ़ोटोमी" },
{ "question":"A Kind Of Winged Insect Migrating In Swarms And Consuming Vegetation", "answer" : "Locust → टिड्डी" },
{ "question":"The Science Of Reasoning", "answer" : "Logic → तर्क" },
{ "question":"Fear Of Words", "answer" : "Logophobia → " },
{ "question":"One, Who Talks Continuously", "answer" : "Loquacious → बातूनी" },
{ "question":"Talkativeness", "answer" : "Loquacity → " },
{ "question":"A Pleasant Song Used For Causing Children To Sleep", "answer" : "Lullaby → लोरी" },
{ "question":"Eclipse Of Moon", "answer" : "Lunar → चांद्र" },
{ "question":"A Home For Lunatics", "answer" : "Lunatic Asylum → पागलख़ाना" },
{ "question":"Fear Of Dark", "answer" : "Lygophobia → " },
{ "question":"Part‐Song For Several Voices Without Instrumental Accompaniment", "answer" : "Madrigal → " },
{ "question":"An Important Or Influential Person", "answer" : "Magnate → थैलीशाह" },
{ "question":"Great Artistic Work", "answer" : "Magnum Opus → प्रसिद्ध रचना" },
{ "question":"An Unmarried Girl (Especially A Virgin)", "answer" : "Maiden → प्रथम" },
{ "question":"The First Speech Delivered By A Person", "answer" : "Maiden Speech → प्रथम भाषण" },
{ "question":"Fear Of Childbirth", "answer" : "Maieusiophilia → " },
{ "question":"Vague Feeling Of General Physical Discomfort", "answer" : "Malaise → अस्वस्थता" },
{ "question":"A Pharse R Sentence That Is Comical Or Noncensical Because The Speaker Used A Wrong Work That Sounded Something Like A Right Word", "answer" : "Malapropism → " },
{ "question":"Person Who Is Always Dissatisfied", "answer" : "Malcontent → बाग़ी" },
{ "question":"Wishing Harm", "answer" : "Malevolent → द्रोही" },
{ "question":"One Who Pretends Illness To Escape Duty", "answer" : "Malingerer → अपवादक" },
{ "question":"Animals Which Give Milk", "answer" : "Mammals → स्तनधारी" },

{ "question":"A Full Size Model Of A Complete Of Partial Human Figure", "answer" : "Mannequin → पुतला" },
{ "question":"A Paper Written By Hand", "answer" : "Manuscript → हस्तलिपि" },
{ "question":"A Woman Who Murder Her Husband", "answer" : "Mariticide → " },
{ "question":"One, Who Dies For A Noble Cause", "answer" : "Martyr → शहीद" },
{ "question":"The Tendency To Derive Sexual Gratification From One’s Own Pain Or Humiliation", "answer" : "Masochism → स्वपीड़ासक्ति" },
{ "question":"One For Whom Money Is The Most Important Thing", "answer" : "Materialistic → भौतिकवादी" },
{ "question":"Morning Prayer", "answer" : "Matin → मतीन" },
{ "question":"A Cinema Show Which Is Held In The Afternoon", "answer" : "Matinee → तीसरे पहर के नाटक का गायन" },
{ "question":"Morning Prayer In The Church Regularly", "answer" : "Matins → बांधना" },
{ "question":"Murder Of Mother", "answer" : "Matricide → मातृहत्या" },
{ "question":"State Of Being Married", "answer" : "Matrimony → विवाह" },
{ "question":"An Establish Principle", "answer" : "Maxim → कहावत" },
{ "question":"A Low Level Tract Of Uncultivated Grassland", "answer" : "Meadow → मैदानी" },
{ "question":"Relating To Or Belonging To The Middle Ages", "answer" : "Medieval → मध्यकालीन" },
{ "question":"Continuous And Profound Contemplation On Spiritual Matters", "answer" : "Meditation → ध्यान" },
{ "question":"Mania Of Being Important", "answer" : "Megalomania → बड़ाई का ख़ब्त" },
{ "question":"An Extravagant Comedy In Which Action Is More Salient Than Characterization", "answer" : "Melodrama → नाटक" },
{ "question":"Personal Reminiscences In A Narrative From", "answer" : "Memoir → इतिहास" },
{ "question":"A Place For Wild Animals And Birds", "answer" : "Menagerie → जंगली पशुओं का पिंजड़ों में संग्रह" },
{ "question":"Working Only For The Sake Of Money", "answer" : "Mercenary → किराये का" },
{ "question":"A Person Whose Build Is Powerful, Compact And Muscular", "answer" : "Mesomorph → " },
{ "question":"One Who Is Very Careful And Particular", "answer" : "Meticulous → सूक्ष्म" },
{ "question":"A Person Who Makes And Sells Ladies Hats, Etc", "answer" : "Milliner → मेमों की टोपी बनानेवाला" },
{ "question":"A Place Where Coins Are Made", "answer" : "Mint → टकसाल" },
{ "question":"Impudent Girl", "answer" : "Minx → ढीठ लड़की" },
{ "question":"One Who Hates Mankind", "answer" : "Misanthrope → मनुष्यद्रोही" },
{ "question":"Hater Of Mankind", "answer" : "Misanthropist → मानवद्वेषी" },
{ "question":"One Who Spends Very Little", "answer" : "Miser → कंजूस" },
{ "question":"A Hater Of Smoking", "answer" : "Misocapnic → " },
{ "question":"One, Who Hates Marriage", "answer" : "Misogamist → " },
{ "question":"One Who Hates Women", "answer" : "Misogynist → स्री जाति से द्वेष करनेवाला" },
{ "question":"A Person, Who Is Sent To Propagate Religion", "answer" : "Missionary → प्रचारक" },
{ "question":"A Political System In Which A Mob Is The Source Of Control", "answer" : "Mobocracy → " },
{ "question":"Autocracy Governed By A Ruler Who Usually Inherits Authority", "answer" : "Monarchy → साम्राज्य" },
{ "question":"A Building In Which Monks Live", "answer" : "Monastery → मठ" },
{ "question":"Rule By One Person", "answer" : "Monocracy → एक व्यक्ति स शासित राज्य" },
{ "question":"The Practice Of Marrying One At A Time", "answer" : "Monogamy → एक ही बार विवाह करने की प्रथा" },
{ "question":"Person Obsessed With One Idea Or Subject", "answer" : "Monomaniac → एकोंमादी" },
{ "question":"Exclusive Possession Of The Trade In Some Commodity", "answer" : "Monopoly → एकाधिकार" },
{ "question":"A Person Who Believes In One Faith Is Called", "answer" : "Monotheist → एकेश्वरवादी" },
{ "question":"Of Outstanding Significance", "answer" : "Monumental → स्मरणार्थ" },
{ "question":"A Place, Where Dead Bodies Are Kept For Identification", "answer" : "Morgue → मग़रूरता" },
{ "question":"Subject To Death", "answer" : "Mortal → नाशवान" },
{ "question":"A Place, Where Dead Bodies Are Kept For Post Mortem", "answer" : "Mortuary → शवगृह" },
{ "question":"Goddess Of Learning And Arts", "answer" : "Muse → सरस्वती" },
{ "question":"Open Rebellion Of Soldiers And Sailors Against Lawful Authority", "answer" : "Mutiny → गदर" },
{ "question":"A Traditional Story Related To Deities", "answer" : "Myth → मिथक" },
{ "question":"A Person Having Same Name As Another", "answer" : "Namesake → हमनाम" },
{ "question":"A Medicine For Producing Sleep", "answer" : "Narcotic → मादक" },
{ "question":"One Whose Parents Are Domiciled", "answer" : "Native → जन्म का" },

{ "question":"A Badly Behaved Child", "answer" : "Naughty → शरारती" },
{ "question":"Fear Of Dead Body", "answer" : "Necrophobia → " },
{ "question":"Government By Inexperienced Persons Is Called", "answer" : "Neocracy → " },
{ "question":"New Word Coined By An Author", "answer" : "Neologism → निओलगिज़्म" },
{ "question":"Using Of New Words", "answer" : "Neology → निओलजी" },
{ "question":"Any New Participant In Some Activity", "answer" : "Neophyte → नवछात्रा" },
{ "question":"A Hollow Space In A Wall For A", "answer" : "Niche → आला" },
{ "question":"Active At Night", "answer" : "Nocturnal → रात का" },
{ "question":"A Strong Desire To Return Home, Home Sickness", "answer" : "Nostalgia → विषाद" },
{ "question":"Person Publically Authorized To Draw Up Or Attest Contracts Etc", "answer" : "Notary → नोटरी" },
{ "question":"Ill-Fame", "answer" : "Notoriety → बदनामी" },
{ "question":"Known Widely And Usually Unfavorably", "answer" : "Notorious → कुख्यात" },
{ "question":"Someone New To A Field Or Activity", "answer" : "Novice → नौसिखिए" },
{ "question":"One, New To Anything, Inexperienced", "answer" : "Novice Or Tyro → नौसिखिया या नौसिखिए" },
{ "question":"The Study Of Coins", "answer" : "Numismatics → न्यूमिज़माटिक्स" },
{ "question":"One Who Collects Coins", "answer" : "Numismatists → " },
{ "question":"Article Of Food Rich In Nutrition", "answer" : "Nutritive → पुष्टिकर" },
{ "question":"Fear Of Darkness", "answer" : "Nyctophobia → " },
{ "question":"A Long Pole Used For Rowing A Boat", "answer" : "Oar → डांड़" },
{ "question":"Fertile Spot In Desert", "answer" : "Oasis → शाद्वल" },
{ "question":"Having Lot Of Fat In One's Body", "answer" : "Obesity → मोटापा" },
{ "question":"An Account In The Newspaper Of The Funeral Of The One Deceased", "answer" : "Obituary → मृत्युलेख" },
{ "question":"Destroy Without Any Trace", "answer" : "Obliterate → काटना" },
{ "question":"A person who is unaware of everything", "answer" : "Oblivious → बेख़बर" },
{ "question":"No Longer In Use", "answer" : "Obsolete → अप्रचलित" },
{ "question":"Physician Who Delivers Babies", "answer" : "Obstetrician → दाई" },
{ "question":"Study Of Ocean", "answer" : "Oceanography → औशेयनोग्रफ़ी" },
{ "question":"Fear Of Crowds", "answer" : "Ochlophobia → " },
{ "question":"A Person Who Is Of An Age From 80 To 90", "answer" : "Octogenarian → अस्सी साल का बुढ़ा" },
{ "question":"Eight-Armed Sea-Creature", "answer" : "Octopus → ऑक्टोपस" },
{ "question":"One Who Cure Eye Disease", "answer" : "Oculist → नेत्र-विशेषज्ञ" },
{ "question":"Study Of Teeth", "answer" : "Odontology → ओडोंटलजी" },
{ "question":"Fear Of Pain", "answer" : "Odynophobia → " },
{ "question":"A Long Wandering Journey", "answer" : "Odyssey → ओडिसी" },
{ "question":"A Political System Governed By A Few People", "answer" : "Oligarchy → कुलीनतंत्र" },
{ "question":"One, Who Is All Powerful", "answer" : "Omnipotent → सर्वशक्तिमान" },
{ "question":"One, Who Is Present Everywhere", "answer" : "Omnipresent → सर्व-भूत" },
{ "question":"Infinite Knowledge", "answer" : "Omniscience → सर्व-ज्ञानी" },
{ "question":"One, Who Knows Everything", "answer" : "Omniscient → सर्वज्ञ" },
{ "question":"One, Who Eats Everything", "answer" : "Omnivorous → सर्व-भक्षक" },
{ "question":"A person who interprets dreams", "answer" : "Oneirocritic → " },
{ "question":"That Which Cannot Be Seen Through", "answer" : "Opaque → अपारदर्शी" },
{ "question":"Fear Of Snakes", "answer" : "Ophiophobia → " },
{ "question":"One Who Treats Diseases Of The Eye", "answer" : "Ophthalmologist → नेत्र रोग विशेषज्ञ" },
{ "question":"Study Of Eye", "answer" : "Ophthalmology → नेत्र विज्ञान" },
{ "question":"Science Of Sight And Light", "answer" : "Optic → ऑप्टिक" },
{ "question":"One Who Tests Eyesight And Sells Spectacles", "answer" : "Optician → प्रकाशविज्ञानशास्री" },
{ "question":"Study Of Light", "answer" : "Optics → प्रकाशिकी" },
{ "question":"A Person Who Looks At The Brighter Side Of Things", "answer" : "Optimist → आशावादी" },
{ "question":"One Who Makes An Eloquent Public Speech", "answer" : "Orator → वक्ता" },

{ "question":"A Field Or A Part Of A Garden Where Fruit Trees Grow", "answer" : "Orchard → बाग" },
{ "question":"The Ceremony At Which A Man Becomes A Priest", "answer" : "Ordination → समन्वय" },
{ "question":"A Factory Where Military Materials Are Produced", "answer" : "Ordnance → तोपख़ाने का" },
{ "question":"A Person Of Asian, Especially East Asian, Descent", "answer" : "Oriental → ओरिएंटल" },
{ "question":"The Branch Of Zoology That Studies Birds", "answer" : "Ornithology → पक्षीविज्ञान" },
{ "question":"Study Of Mountain", "answer" : "Orography → " },
{ "question":"One, Who Has Lost Parents", "answer" : "Orphan → अनाथ" },
{ "question":"A Home For Orphans", "answer" : "Orphanage → अनाथालय" },
{ "question":"Specialist Who Straightens Teeth", "answer" : "Orthodontist → ओथडोटिस" },
{ "question":"Study Of Correct Spelling Of Words", "answer" : "Orthography → इमला" },
{ "question":"Medical Specialty Dealing With Bones And Joints", "answer" : "Orthopedics → अस्थियों" },
{ "question":"Fear Of Property", "answer" : "Orthophobia → " },
{ "question":"One, Who Looks After Horses At An Inn", "answer" : "Ostler → साईस" },
{ "question":"To Expel From Society", "answer" : "Ostracize → समाज से बाहर निकालना" },
{ "question":"A Large Bird Reputed To Bury Its Head In Sand When Pursued", "answer" : "Ostrich → शुतुरमुर्ग" },
{ "question":"Dungeon Entered By Trapdoor", "answer" : "Oubliette → उब्लियट" },
{ "question":"Cast Out As Useless", "answer" : "Outcast → निर्वासित" },
{ "question":"Policeman Riding On Motorcycles As Guards To A Vip", "answer" : "Outriders → " },
{ "question":"One Who Believes In Total Abolition Of War", "answer" : "Pacifist → शांतिवादी" },
{ "question":"A Person, Who Is Specialist In Child Diseases", "answer" : "Paediatrician → बाल रोग विशेषज्ञ" },
{ "question":"Person Who Does Not Believe In Any", "answer" : "Pagan → बुतपरस्त" },
{ "question":"Food Which Agrees With One’s Taste", "answer" : "Palatable → स्वादिष्ट" },
{ "question":"The Study Of Ancient Writing", "answer" : "Paleography → प्राचीन शिलालेखों का अध्ययन" },
{ "question":"Study Of Fossils", "answer" : "Paleontology → जीवाश्म विज्ञान" },
{ "question":"A Remedy For All Diseases", "answer" : "Panacea → रामबाण" },
{ "question":"Government Run Universally", "answer" : "Panarchy → " },
{ "question":"A Speech Or Writing Praising A Person Or A Thing", "answer" : "Panegyric → स्तुतिपाठ" },
{ "question":"Person Who Belives That God Is Everything And Eveyting Is God", "answer" : "Pantheist → " },
{ "question":"A Dumb Show", "answer" : "Pantomime → मूकाभिनय" },
{ "question":"A Lover Specially One Who Unlawfully Takes The Position Of A Wife Or A Husband", "answer" : "Paramour → प्रेमिका" },
{ "question":"One Who Lives On Others", "answer" : "Parasite → परजीवी" },
{ "question":"A Lady’s Umbrella Is", "answer" : "Parasol → छत्र" },
{ "question":"Funny Imitation Of A Poem", "answer" : "Parody → हास्यानुकृति" },
{ "question":"Pledge Given By A Prisoner For Temporary Release, Not To Escape", "answer" : "Parole → पैरोल" },
{ "question":"Murder Of One’s Parents", "answer" : "Parricide → देश-द्रोही" },
{ "question":"Sole Right To Make And Sell Some Invention", "answer" : "Patent → पेटेंट" },
{ "question":"One Who Examines Tissues Under A Microscope To Diagnose Disease", "answer" : "Pathologist → चिकित्सक" },
{ "question":"Study Of Disease", "answer" : "Pathology → पैथोलॉजी" },
{ "question":"Murder Of Father", "answer" : "Patricide → पिता का वध" },
{ "question":"Property Inherited From Forefathers", "answer" : "Patrimony → विरासत" },
{ "question":"One Who Loves Own Country", "answer" : "Patriot → देश-भक्त" },
{ "question":"A Person Who Is Very Poor", "answer" : "Pauper → कंगाल" },
{ "question":"Principles Of Teaching", "answer" : "Pedagogy → शिक्षणशास्र" },
{ "question":"One, Who Makes A Vain Display Of His Knowledge", "answer" : "Pedant → रूढ़िवादी" },
{ "question":"A Style In Which A Writer Makes A Display Of His Knowledge", "answer" : "Pedantic → पंडिताऊ" },
{ "question":"One, Who Goes On Foot", "answer" : "Pedestrian → पैदल यात्री" },
{ "question":"The Specialist Who Treats Childhood Illnesses", "answer" : "Pediatrician → बच्चों का चिकित्सक" },
{ "question":"To Remove The Skin Of A Potato Or And Orange", "answer" : "Peel → छाल" },
{ "question":"Equal In Rank", "answer" : "Peer → सहकर्मी" },
{ "question":"A Small Enclosure For Cattle ,Sheep ,Polutry Etc", "answer" : "Pen → लेखनी" },

{ "question":"Fear Of Poverty", "answer" : "Peniaphobia → " },
{ "question":"Land So Surrounded By Water As To E Almost And Island", "answer" : "Peninsula → प्रायद्वीप" },
{ "question":"Payment Made In Consideration Of Past Service", "answer" : "Pension → पेंशन" },
{ "question":"A Specialist Who Treats Diseases Of The Gum", "answer" : "Periodontist → परिदंतशोथ" },
{ "question":"Be The Embodiment Or Perfect Example", "answer" : "Personify → आदर्शरूप ग्रहण करना" },
{ "question":"A Person Who Looks At The Darker Side Of Things", "answer" : "Pessimist → निराशावादी" },
{ "question":"Fear Of Becoming Bald", "answer" : "Phalacrophobia → " },
{ "question":"One Who Engages In Extramarital Sex", "answer" : "Philander → भ्रष्टाचार करना" },
{ "question":"One, Who Amuses Himself By Love Making", "answer" : "Philanderer → पुच्छलगा" },
{ "question":"One Who Is Interested In Charitable Works", "answer" : "Philanthropist → लोकोपकारक" },
{ "question":"One, Who Collects Stamps", "answer" : "Philatelist → डाक के टिकट का संग्रहक" },
{ "question":"Study Of Stamp Collection", "answer" : "Philately → टिकट इकट्ठा करने का काम" },
{ "question":"One Who Does Not Care For Art And Literature", "answer" : "Philistine → अशिक्षित" },
{ "question":"A Lover Of Womankind", "answer" : "Philogynist → स्रियों का प्रेमी" },
{ "question":"One Who Works For The Welfare Of The Women", "answer" : "Philogynist /Feminist → स्रियों का प्रेमी / नारीवादी" },
{ "question":"The Study Of Languages", "answer" : "Philology → भाषाशास्त्र" },
{ "question":"A Lover Of Learning", "answer" : "Philomath → " },
{ "question":"A Lover Of Property And Art", "answer" : "Philomuse → " },
{ "question":"A Lover Of Arts", "answer" : "Philotechnic → " },
{ "question":"A Lover Of God", "answer" : "Philotheist → " },
{ "question":"A Lover Of Animals", "answer" : "Philozoic → " },
{ "question":"Fear Of Writing Graph", "answer" : "Phobia → भय" },
{ "question":"Study Of Sound", "answer" : "Phonetics, Acoustics → फोनेटिक्स, ध्वनिकी" },
{ "question":"The Science Of Judging Of A Person’s Character Capabilities Etc", "answer" : "Phrenology → मस्तिष्क-विज्ञान" },
{ "question":"The Study Of Human Face", "answer" : "Physiognomy → मुख का आकृति" },
{ "question":"The Science Dealing With The Functioning Of Organisms", "answer" : "Physiology → फिजियोलॉजी" },
{ "question":"Ride On Someone’s Back", "answer" : "Piggyback → " },
{ "question":"A Thief Who Steals Without Using Violence", "answer" : "Pilferer → चोर" },
{ "question":"One Who Journeys To A Holy Place", "answer" : "Pilgrim → यात्री" },
{ "question":"One Who Does Something First", "answer" : "Pioneer → अगुआ" },
{ "question":"Act Of Turning Hostility Into Friendly Feelings", "answer" : "Placation → " },
{ "question":"Literary Theft Or Passing Off An Author's Original Work As One's Own", "answer" : "Plagiarism → साहित्यक डाकाज़नी" },
{ "question":"Someone Who Uses Another Person's Words Or Ideas As If They Were His Own", "answer" : "Plagiarist → साहित्यिक चोर" },
{ "question":"Ordinary Remarks Often Repeated", "answer" : "Platitude → साधारण बात" },
{ "question":"Common Place Remarks", "answer" : "Platitudes → " },
{ "question":"Egg-Laying Mammal", "answer" : "Platypus → एक प्रकार का बत्तक-सदृश नाक से पशु" },
{ "question":"A Decision Made By Votes Of All Qualified Citizens", "answer" : "Plebiscite → जनमत-संग्रह" },
{ "question":"A Person With Full Discretionary Power To Act On Behalf Of A Country", "answer" : "Plenipotentiary → साधिकार" },
{ "question":"Use Of More Words Than Are Needed To Express The Meaning", "answer" : "Pleonasm → शब्द-बाहुल्य" },
{ "question":"Government By The Rich", "answer" : "Plutocracy → धनिक तन्त्र" },
{ "question":"Stand For A Speaker", "answer" : "Podium → मंच" },
{ "question":"The Practice Of Marrying More Than One Husband At A Time", "answer" : "Polyandry → एक से अधिक जीवित पति रखने की बात या अवस्था" },
{ "question":"The Practice Of Marrying More Than One Wife At A Time", "answer" : "Polygamy → बहुविवाह" },
{ "question":"One, Who Speaks Many Languages", "answer" : "Polyglot → बहुभाषी" },
{ "question":"A Figure With Many Angles Or Sides", "answer" : "Polygon → बहुभुज" },
{ "question":"A Place Where Ships Seek Shelter", "answer" : "Port → बंदरगाह" },
{ "question":"That Can Be Carried Easily", "answer" : "Portable → पोर्टेबल" },
{ "question":"A Number Of Policemen Called To Quell A Riot", "answer" : "Posse → मेला" },
{ "question":"A Child Born After The Death Of His Father Or The Book Published After The Death Of The Writer", "answer" : "Posthumous → मरणोत्तर" },
{ "question":"A Book Published After The Death Of Its Author", "answer" : "Posthumus → पोस्थुमस" },

{ "question":"An Examination Of Dead Body", "answer" : "Post-Mortem → शव परीक्षा" },
{ "question":"A Note Appended To A Letter After The Signature", "answer" : "Postscript → उपसंहार" },
{ "question":"Something Which Can Be Taken For Granted", "answer" : "Postulate → मांगना" },
{ "question":"Fit To Drink", "answer" : "Potable → पीने योग्य" },
{ "question":"A Book Or Picture Produced Merely To Bring In Money", "answer" : "Pot‐Boiler → पॉट-बॉयलर" },
{ "question":"A Person Concerned With Practical Results And Values", "answer" : "Pragmatist → दंभी" },
{ "question":"Any Animal That Lives By Preying On Other Animals", "answer" : "Predator → दरिंदा" },
{ "question":"To Form An Opinion Against Anybody Baselessly", "answer" : "Prejudice → पक्षपात" },
{ "question":"Explicit Understanding To Do Something", "answer" : "Promise → वादा" },
{ "question":"Prohibition Against Something Injurious", "answer" : "Proscription → बहिष्कार" },
{ "question":"Take Legal Action Against Somebody", "answer" : "Prosecute → पर मुकदमा चलाने" },
{ "question":"Woman Who Offers The Use Of Her Body For Sexual Intercourse To Any One Who Will Pay For This", "answer" : "Prostitute → पतुरिया" },
{ "question":"Food For Farm Animals", "answer" : "Provender → चारा" },
{ "question":"One Who Studies The Pattern Of Voting In Elections", "answer" : "Psephologist → चुनाव विश्लेषक" },
{ "question":"The Branch Of Sociology That Studies Election Trends", "answer" : "Psephology → " },
{ "question":"An Imaginary Name Assumed By An Author For Disguise", "answer" : "Pseudonym → उपनाम" },
{ "question":"One Who Treats Mental And Emotional Disturbances", "answer" : "Psychiatrist → मनोचिकित्सक" },
{ "question":"One Who Studies The Science Of Mind", "answer" : "Psychologist → मनोविज्ञानी" },
{ "question":"Antisocial Person Who May Commit Criminal Acts", "answer" : "Psychopath, Sociopath → मनोरोगी, Sociopath" },
{ "question":"Inclined To Fight Or Be Aggressive", "answer" : "Pugnacity → कलह की इच्छा" },
{ "question":"One Who Is Particular About The Purity Of One's Language", "answer" : "Purist → शुद्धतावादी" },
{ "question":"One Who Pretends Skill In Medicine And Surgery", "answer" : "Quack → नीमहकीम" },
{ "question":"Animal Having Four Foot", "answer" : "Quadruped → चौपाया" },
{ "question":"An Act Of Separation From Other Persons To Avoid Infection", "answer" : "Quarantine → संगरोध करना" },
{ "question":"Stanza Of Four Lines", "answer" : "Quatrain → रुबाई" },
{ "question":"Formulated Series Of Questions", "answer" : "Questionnaire → प्रश्नावली" },
{ "question":"A Feather Used As A Pen", "answer" : "Quill → मोड़ना" },
{ "question":"Fixed Number Of Person That Must Be Present To Make Proceedings Valid", "answer" : "Quorum → कोरम" },
{ "question":"People In Rowdy Science", "answer" : "Rabble → भीड़" },
{ "question":"Emission Of Light Or Heat From Central Point", "answer" : "Radiation → विकिरण" },
{ "question":"Lottery In Which An Article Is Assigned By Lot To One Of Those Buying Tickets", "answer" : "Raffle /Draw → क्रीड़ा / ड्रा" },
{ "question":"To Use A Woman By Force", "answer" : "Rape → बलात्कार" },
{ "question":"One Who Takes Up Arms Against Government", "answer" : "Rebel → विद्रोही" },
{ "question":"Person Who Lives Alone And Avoid Others", "answer" : "Recluse → वैरागी" },
{ "question":"Too Much Official Formalities", "answer" : "Red-Tapism → लालफीताशाही" },
{ "question":"Dress With Medals, Ribbons Worn At Official Ceremonies", "answer" : "Regalia → इनाम" },
{ "question":"Murder Of King Or Queen", "answer" : "Regicide → राज-हत्या" },
{ "question":"Give Back To The Users Their Youthful Vigor And Appearance", "answer" : "Rejuvenate → फिर से युवा करना" },
{ "question":"One Who Forsakes Religion", "answer" : "Renegade → पाखण्डी" },
{ "question":"Witty , Clever Retort", "answer" : "Repartee → हाजिर जवाबी" },
{ "question":"A Light Sailing Boat Built Especially For Racing Yacht Atonement For One’s Sins", "answer" : "Repentance → पछतावा" },
{ "question":"A State In Which Supreme Power Is Held By The People And Their Elected Representatives, And Which Has An Elected Or Nominated President Rather Than A Monarch", "answer" : "Republic → गणतंत्र" },
{ "question":"Shining , Brilliant And Magnificent", "answer" : "Resplendent → देदीप्यमान" },
{ "question":"Give Tit For Tat", "answer" : "Retaliate → प्रतिकार करना" },
{ "question":"A Person Who Is Reserved In Talks", "answer" : "Reticent → अल्पभाषी" },
{ "question":"A Lady’s Purse", "answer" : "Reticule → " },
{ "question":"Which Takes Effect From Some Earlier Date", "answer" : "Retrospective → पूर्वप्रभावी" },
{ "question":"A Radical Change Or Political Upheaval", "answer" : "Revolution → क्रांति" },
{ "question":"The Art Of Elegant Speech Or Writing", "answer" : "Rhetoric → वक्रपटुता" },
{ "question":"An Intelligent And Obedient Machine Like A Man", "answer" : "Robot → रोबोट" },

{ "question":"A String Of Beads Used For Counting Prayers", "answer" : "Rosary → माला" },
{ "question":"Violating Or Profaning Religious Things/Places", "answer" : "Sacrilege → अपवित्रीकरण" },
{ "question":"One Who Helps Others Good", "answer" : "Samaritan → सामरी" },
{ "question":"A Place For The Sick To Recover Health", "answer" : "Sanatorium → आरोग्यआश्रम" },
{ "question":"A Place Of Refuge Recognized As Secure", "answer" : "Sanctuary → मंदिर" },
{ "question":"A Platform For Hanging Criminals", "answer" : "Scaffold → पाड़" },
{ "question":"One Who Is Given To Questioning The Truth Of Facts And The Soundness Of Inferences", "answer" : "Sceptic → संदेहवादी" },
{ "question":"Someone Who Knows A Lot About The Subject", "answer" : "Scholar → छात्र" },
{ "question":"Write Hurriedly Or Carelessly In Regard To Hand Writing", "answer" : "Scribble → घसीटना" },
{ "question":"One, Who Cuts In Stones", "answer" : "Sculptor → संगतराश" },
{ "question":"Which Does Not Favour Anyone Religion", "answer" : "Secular → धर्म निरपेक्ष" },
{ "question":"An Instrument For Measuring Movements Of The Ground", "answer" : "Seismograph → भूकंप-सूचक यंत्र" },
{ "question":"One Who Studies The Meanings Of Words", "answer" : "Semanticist → " },
{ "question":"Music Played Or Sung At Night Below A Person’s Window", "answer" : "Serenade → प्रेमी का सन्ध्या का गीत" },
{ "question":"Breeding Of Silkworm For Silk Production", "answer" : "Sericulture → रेशम उत्पादन" },
{ "question":"A Stanza Of Six Lines", "answer" : "Sestet → " },
{ "question":"A Case In Which The Sword Is Kept", "answer" : "Sheath → म्यान" },
{ "question":"A Case In Which The Blade Of A Sword Is Kept Sheath", "answer" : "Sheath / Scabbard → म्यान / म्यान" },
{ "question":"Cutting All The Waste Paper Into Pieces", "answer" : "Shredding → कतरन" },
{ "question":"A Woman With Peevish Nature", "answer" : "Shrew → कर्कशा" },
{ "question":"Go Back And Forth", "answer" : "Shuttle → शटल" },
{ "question":"Sleep Enjoyed In The Afternoon", "answer" : "Siesta → गरम देशों में दोपहर की अल्प निद्रा" },
{ "question":"A Portrait Of A Person With Only The Outline Of The Profile", "answer" : "Silhouette → सिल्हूट" },
{ "question":"Happening At The Same Time", "answer" : "Simultaneous → समकालिक" },
{ "question":"A Job With High Salary But Little Responsibility", "answer" : "Sinecure → ऐसा पद जिस में वेतन मिले परन्तु कुछ काम न करना पड़े" },
{ "question":"Someone Who Imports Or Exports Without Paying Duties", "answer" : "Smuggler → तस्कर" },
{ "question":"One Who Despises Persons Of Lower Social Position", "answer" : "Snob → मोची का नौकर" },
{ "question":"One Who Studies Social Conditions", "answer" : "Sociologist → समाजशास्त्री" },
{ "question":"A Short Stay At A Place", "answer" : "Sojourn → डेरा डालना" },
{ "question":"Eclipse Of Sun", "answer" : "Solar → सौर" },
{ "question":"Speaking Himself When Alone", "answer" : "Soliloquy → स्वगत भाषण" },
{ "question":"A Piece Of Music By One Person", "answer" : "Solo → एकल" },
{ "question":"Sleepwalking", "answer" : "Somnambulism → नींद में चलना" },
{ "question":"A Person, Who Walks In Sleep", "answer" : "Somnambulist → नींद में चलनेवाला" },
{ "question":"Talking In Sleep", "answer" : "Somniloquism → " },
{ "question":"A Person, Who Talks In Sleep", "answer" : "Somniloquist → " },
{ "question":"Causing Or Tending To Cause Sleep", "answer" : "Soporific → ऊंघता हुआ" },
{ "question":"Killing of One's sister", "answer" : "Sorocide → " },
{ "question":"Murder Of Sister", "answer" : "Sororicide → " },
{ "question":"One, Who Is A Habitual Drunkard", "answer" : "Sot, Toper → पियक्कड़, शराबी" },
{ "question":"One Who Is A Habitual Drunker", "answer" : "Sottoper → " },
{ "question":"A Thing Kept As A Reminder Of A Person, Place Or Event", "answer" : "Souvenir → यादगार" },
{ "question":"Image Formed By Rays Of Light", "answer" : "Spectrum → स्पेक्ट्रम" },
{ "question":"A Person Who Spends His Money Recklessly", "answer" : "Spendthrift, Prodigal → उड़ाऊ, खर्चीला" },
{ "question":"Lady Who Remains Unmarried", "answer" : "Spinster → कातनेवाली" },
{ "question":"One Who Speaks On Behalf Of Others", "answer" : "Spokesman → प्रवक्ता" },
{ "question":"A Place For Horses", "answer" : "Stable → स्थिर" },
{ "question":"To Make Free From Living Germs Or Bacteria", "answer" : "Sterilize → बाँझ बनाना" },
{ "question":"One Who Loads And Unloads Ships", "answer" : "Stevedore → जहाज़ पर का माल उतारने-चढ़ानेवाला" },
{ "question":"A Person Who Insists On Something", "answer" : "Stickler → हामी" },

{ "question":"A Mark Of Shame", "answer" : "Stigma → कलंक" },
{ "question":"A Person, Who Is Indifferent To Pleasure And Pain And Has Control Over His Passions", "answer" : "Stoic → उदासीन" },
{ "question":"Indifference To Pleasure Or Pain", "answer" : "Stoicism → वैराग्य" },
{ "question":"Walk In A Vain , Self‐Important Way", "answer" : "Strut → अकड़" },
{ "question":"A Heavy Unnatural Slumber", "answer" : "Stupor → व्यामोह" },
{ "question":"A Place Where Pigs Are Kept", "answer" : "Sty → शूकरशाला" },
{ "question":"Submarines Operate Below The Surface Of The Seas", "answer" : "Subterranean → भूमिगत" },
{ "question":"Murder Of Oneself", "answer" : "Suicide → आत्महत्या" },
{ "question":"A Substitute", "answer" : "Surrogate → सरोगेट" },
{ "question":"The Last Work (Literary) Of A Writer", "answer" : "Swan Song → हंस गीत" },
{ "question":"A Large Group Of Insects Moving In A Mass", "answer" : "Swarm → झुंड" },
{ "question":"A Boastful Fellow", "answer" : "Swashbuckler → गलाकाटू" },
{ "question":"To Slap With A Flat Object", "answer" : "Swat → शक्तिशाली प्रहार" },
{ "question":"Occurring At The Same Time Or Rate", "answer" : "Synchronous → एक समय का" },
{ "question":"A Council Of Clergymen", "answer" : "Synod → पादरियों की सभा" },
{ "question":"Words Which Have The Same Meaning", "answer" : "Synonyms → समानार्थी" },
{ "question":"A Place Where Lather Is Tanned", "answer" : "Tannery → चमड़े का कारख़ाना" },
{ "question":"The Art Of Preserving Skin", "answer" : "Taxidermy → चर्मपूर्ण करना" },
{ "question":"One Who Does Not Take Alcoholic Drinks", "answer" : "Teetotaller → मद्यत्यागी" },
{ "question":"One, Who Does Not Take Any Intoxicating Drink", "answer" : "Teetotaller → मद्यत्यागी" },
{ "question":"Power Of Reading Thoughts Of Others", "answer" : "Telepathy → टेलिपाथी" },
{ "question":"An Instrument Of Seeing Distant Objects", "answer" : "Telescope → दूरबीन" },
{ "question":"One Who Enjoy Talking About Others Private Affairs", "answer" : "Telltale → गप्पी" },
{ "question":"A Noisy Quarrelsome Women, A Shrew", "answer" : "Termagant → लड़ाका" },
{ "question":"Station At The End Of A Route", "answer" : "Terminus → अंतिम स्टेशन" },
{ "question":"Fear Of Deaths", "answer" : "Thanatophobia → " },
{ "question":"One Who Believes In The Existence Of A God Or Gods", "answer" : "Theist → आस्तिक" },
{ "question":"Government By Religious Principles", "answer" : "Theocracy → थेअक्रसी" },
{ "question":"Government By The Gods", "answer" : "Therachy → " },
{ "question":"An Instrument For Measuring Temperature", "answer" : "Thermometer → थर्मामीटर" },
{ "question":"Fasten Or Secure With A Rope, String, Or Cord", "answer" : "Tie → टाई" },
{ "question":"One Who Always Runs Away From Danger", "answer" : "Timid → डरपोक" },
{ "question":"Pleasurable Stimulation", "answer" : "Titillation → गुदगुदाना" },
{ "question":"Existing Only In Name", "answer" : "Titular → नाममात्र का" },
{ "question":"A Dull, Heavy Book", "answer" : "Tome → मुझसे" },
{ "question":"One Who Is Habitual Drunken", "answer" : "Toper/Sot → शराबी / सोत" },
{ "question":"Art Of Cutting Tree And Bushes Into Ornamental Shape", "answer" : "Topiary → " },
{ "question":"A Writing Which End In Death Or Sorrow", "answer" : "Tragedy → त्रासदी" },
{ "question":"Allowing Light To Pass Through Diffusely", "answer" : "Translucent → पारभासी" },
{ "question":"The Doctrine That Human Souls Pass From One Body To Another At The Time Of Death", "answer" : "Transmigration → स्थानांतरगमन" },
{ "question":"A Drawing On Transparent Paper", "answer" : "Transparency → ट्रांसपेरेंसी" },
{ "question":"That Which Can Be Seen Through", "answer" : "Transparent → पारदर्शक" },
{ "question":"An Event Which Happens Once In Three Years", "answer" : "Triennial → त्रैवार्षिक" },
{ "question":"Group Of Three Novels", "answer" : "Trilogy → त्रयी" },
{ "question":"Having Three Legs", "answer" : "Tripod → तिपाई" },
{ "question":"Fear Of Numbers", "answer" : "Triskaidekaphobia → " },
{ "question":"A Person/Student Who Absents Himself From Class Or Duty Without Permission", "answer" : "Truant → अनुपस्थित रहने" },
{ "question":"Plain Or Self Evident Truth", "answer" : "Truism → " },
{ "question":"Confidence Reposed In Person By Making Them Nominal Owner", "answer" : "Trust → भरोसा" },
{ "question":"A Disloyal Person Who Betrays Or Deserts His Cause", "answer" : "Turncoat → " },

{ "question":"Two Children Born Together", "answer" : "Twins → जुड़वां" },
{ "question":"Science Of Printing", "answer" : "Typography → टाइपोग्राफी" },
{ "question":"Found Or Present Everywhere", "answer" : "Ubiquitous → देशव्यापी" },
{ "question":"All Of One Mind", "answer" : "Unanimous → सर्वसम्मत" },
{ "question":"Incapable Of Being Avoided", "answer" : "Unavoidable → अनिवार्य" },
{ "question":"Decision Taken By One's Side Only", "answer" : "Unilateral → एकतरफा" },
{ "question":"Belonging To All Parts Of The World", "answer" : "Universal → यूनिवर्सल" },
{ "question":"Having Information Till Today", "answer" : "Up-To-Date → आधुनिक" },
{ "question":"The Study Of Mountains", "answer" : "Urology → उरोलोजि" },
{ "question":"One Who Lends Money At Higher Rate Of Interest", "answer" : "Usurer → सूदखोर" },
{ "question":"A Person Who Seize Something Without The Right To Do So", "answer" : "Usurper → हड़पनेवाला" },
{ "question":"An Imaginary Perfect Social And Political System", "answer" : "Utopia → आदर्शलोक" },
{ "question":"Murder Of Wife", "answer" : "Uxoricide → " },
{ "question":"One Extremely Fond Of One's Wife", "answer" : "Uxorious → " },
{ "question":"Change One’s Mind Two Quickly", "answer" : "Vacillation → चंचलता" },
{ "question":"A Person Who Lives A Wandering Life", "answer" : "Vagabond → आवारा" },
{ "question":"A Farewell Speech", "answer" : "Valedictory → विदा का" },
{ "question":"Weak Or Sickly Person Especially One Morbidly Concerned With His Or Her Health", "answer" : "Valetudinarian → वहमी" },
{ "question":"Someone Who Willfully Destroys Or Defaces Property", "answer" : "Vandal → बर्बर" },
{ "question":"Someone Who Eats No Meat Or Fish", "answer" : "Vegetarian → शाकाहारी" },
{ "question":"A Fault That May Be Forgiven", "answer" : "Venial → अमर" },
{ "question":"The Meat Of Deer", "answer" : "Venison → हिरन का मांस" },
{ "question":"A Performer Who Projects The Voice Into A Wooden Dummy", "answer" : "Ventriloquist → " },
{ "question":"Repetition Of Word By Word, word for word", "answer" : "Verbatim → प्रतिशब्द" },
{ "question":"Style Full Of Words", "answer" : "Verbose → वाचाल" },
{ "question":"Interested In And Clever At Many Different Things", "answer" : "Versatile → बहुमुखी" },
{ "question":"Animals Having Spinal Column", "answer" : "Vertebrate → हड्डीवाला" },
{ "question":"Evening Prayer In A Church", "answer" : "Vesper → संध्या का तारा" },
{ "question":"One, Who Has A Long Experience Of Any Occupation", "answer" : "Veteran → वयोवृद्ध" },
{ "question":"A Short Literary Description Marked By Delicacy", "answer" : "Vignette → शब्दचित्र" },
{ "question":"One Who Is Determined To Exact Full Vegeance For Wrong Done To Him", "answer" : "Vindictive → प्रतिशोधी" },
{ "question":"One Who Deals In Wines", "answer" : "Vintner → " },
{ "question":"A Woman Who Has No Sexual Experience", "answer" : "Virgin → अछूता" },
{ "question":"One Who Is Brilliant Performer On Stage (Specially Music)", "answer" : "Virtuoso → कलाप्रवीण व्यक्ति" },
{ "question":"One, Who Offers One's Services", "answer" : "Volunteer → स्वयंसेवक" },
{ "question":"Person Who Gives Himself Up To Luxury And Sexual Pleasures", "answer" : "Voluptuary → " },
{ "question":"One Who Is Very Eager For Knowledge And Reads A Lot", "answer" : "Voracious → पेटू" },
{ "question":"A Long Journy Especially By Sea", "answer" : "Voyage → जलयात्रा" },
{ "question":"A Place For Clothes", "answer" : "Wardrobe → कपड़े" },
{ "question":"A Cock-Shaped Indicator On The Building Top To Show The Direction Of Air", "answer" : "Weather-Cock → मौसम मुर्गा" },
{ "question":"A Person Sharing Responsibility For A Political Party’s Discipline And Tactics", "answer" : "Whip → कोड़ा" },
{ "question":"A Woman Whose Husband Has Died", "answer" : "Widow → विधवा" },
{ "question":"A Man Whose Wife Has Died", "answer" : "Widower → विधुर" },
{ "question":"Method Of Sending Messages Without The Help Of Wires", "answer" : "Wireless Or Radio → वायरलेस या रेडियो" },
{ "question":"To Move Along With Quick Short Twisting Actions", "answer" : "Wriggle → " },
{ "question":"Fear Of God", "answer" : "Zeusophobia → " },
{ "question":"A Belt Of The Heavenly Bodies Divided Into Equal Signs", "answer" : "Zodiac → राशि चक्र" },
{ "question":"A Place Where Birds And Animals Are Kept", "answer" : "Zoo → चिड़ियाघर" },
{ "question":"One Who Studies The Science Of History Of Animals Of Mountains Till It Melts After Passing The Snow Line", "answer" : "Zoologist → जीव विज्ञानी" },
{ "question":"The Branch Of Biology That Studies Animals", "answer" : "Zoology → जंतु शास्र" }]
